Introduction

12020 Journals

 Words are the clothes thoughts wear

 I shall not lose perspective of the reality of my convictions

Author's Note

         I started this program of devotional rituals . . . keeping records of my daily activities like major lessons learned in a journal (a later inclusion), and writing. This was on the 1st of January of 2020. I lose my laptop in a robbery incident, leaving me with no device to continue my resolve. In the early hours of Sunday, January 19, 2020, armed robbers burgle my home, leaving with my laptop, phone, among other valuable items removed from the property. I was in disarray, a result of this perturbation, it takes two weeks, finally I align my resolve to my resolute and continue with my minds work.

         In later considerations on how best to improve my journal, Alighting at the improviso of including poem text when available. In doing this I peel off the web strands of old poems, discovering how important the days I missed were; both on my devotionals and daily poem readings. The acute exposure of this fact has lead me to include this note. I’ll be doing a revision of the days missed, including in this journal what exist nowhere, not in my previous laptop or in some cloud somewhere ;)

         Out of love for poems, I’ll be including my favourite poems from days recorded on my previous laptop.

         In the constant whirls of swivel . . . far from fortuitous, an appending of methods . . . an acquiesce born of progressive inquisition into the techniques of solving inherent problems.

Methods used

Trial and error — The scientific method.

Puzzle-solving — Ariadne's thread.

Philosophical — Stoicism, Nomological.

The most fundamental aggression to ourselves, the most fundamental harm we can do to ourselves, is to remain ignorant by not having the courage and the respect to look at ourselves honestly and gently.

—Pema Chödrön, When Things Fall Apart

If I try to seize this self of which I feel sure, if I try to define and to summarize it, it is nothing but water slipping through my fingers. I can sketch one by one all the aspects it is able to assume, all those likewise that have been attributed to it, this upbringing, this origin, this ardor or these silences, this nobility or this vileness. But aspects cannot be added up.

—Albert Camus, An Absurd Reasoning

Our actual competence at a whole host of different life endeavors is actually inversely proportional to our perceived competence

—Dunning-Krugger effect

Though we travel the world over to find the beautiful, we must carry it with us or we find it not.

—Ralph Waldo Emerson

Thursday, April 2, 2020

Devotional: BE WARY OF WHAT YOU LET IN

Poem of the Day: The Walrus and the Carpenter by Lewis Carroll

Entries:

         The only reason, language still stands in the way of cognition is the inability of rest on the laurels of the bolsters of objectivity.

         Avoid the grinding halt of generalization, the void of context. Language is incomprehensible of knowledge in this nature.

         I was thinking and realized that, if I get to create my own AI; which I will soon, I might as well take a bin of dead information and dispose it in my AI’s cognitive learning table, if I plan on indexing the internet. The real aim should be to impose a strict learning scheme that aims at understanding my cognitive process through language that maps the sequence of detailed pragmatic thought.

         I think the principle or the inclination to ideologies like  unconditional love  are synonymous to “regardless of what you do I’ll hate you.”

         The idea of negating meaning leads to the loss of value. I think the Yoruba tribe’s culture is a nihilistic one, upheld on the guise of myths that are taking literally. A problem of diffused misinformation? An orphic adaption? This takes me to the point in memory—anachronistic, from my benightedness—peculiar of its customs, when a colleague from university, his dad tells me sorry for being a Yoruba native. Now I get the idea, it’s reflected in the demotic expressions of the language.

         I have been so jaded, it’s weird. I haven’t read in a while.

Wednesday, April 8, 2020

Devotional: THE COST OF ACCEPTING COUNTERFEITS

Poem of the Day: Home-Thoughts from Abroad from Robert Browning

Entries:

         An excerpt from today’s devotional reading:  The point of this metaphor is to highlight how much effort we put into making sure money is real, whereas we accept potentially life-changing thoughts or assumptions without so much as a question. One ironic assumption along these lines: that having a lot of money makes you wealthy. Or that because a lot of people believe something, it must be true.  I should be reminded of how over the past few months I’ve been attacked throughout the clock, pushing me to a wall of annihilation, annihilation of not just life, this being the last in the gradient of the destructive process set in motion. I have lost proper expression of my cognitive processes, my thoughts hampered by the constant brainwashing, and inducing of hypnotic states that produce awareness of a  self;  suggested, as not worked on by self, the constant deliberate mass action of hindering any form of progress as an individual, of the individual.

         I have become chafe from having to wait for the visa appointment, it’s been months now, waiting for the online portal registration, amidst all the lies, I have chosen to keep aloof, in the event of things not working out fine, I have plans. Real plans.

         Intelligence is beautiful in all its mystery and misery. Its ever complex intertwines of intricate detail is a glimpse at the ever non ending halls of heaven.

         In a culture without rich literature, devoid of history - relative to civilization - cognition is seated on direct experience, discerning of the perceptual horizon, a myth outside of the collective experience. Without a new experience, there can be no growth. A very possibility is a race of identical individuals with little to no arbitrary difference, outside the physiological. Examining the expressions of beings shouldn’t be taken outside of the domain of thought origin, impulse and backgrounds like profession, family. This being a subculture diagnosis. This could be a clan problem, one of habitual hard drug abuse.

         In today’s poem by Robert Browning, he slates his writing with, quoting: “little children’s dower, far brighter than this gaudy melon flower.” I think this is an allusion to the preferential choice of the civilized world of economics over nature. My expression being a bit vague.

         There’s some form of sympathy for self, when I read something insightful, almost like a resentment of my constant need to read, void of smug.

         Atlas shrugged by Ayn Rand took thirteen years to write, she lives by the philosophy I quote: “ That I have no right to anything, except to run to my desk: No right to breathe, no right to live—that’s my attitude. You stop only when you’re ready to collapse. I imagine it’s like being pregnant: there is something alive that demands priority over everything; you’re under that pressure constantly.  “

Night Visions:

         In my night vision I saw young Adolf, and danced with war prisoners.

It was in the early hours of the morning, a morning jarring wake had left me with nothing to do but to read a book, I picked my phone, swept through the list of available titles, hoping to go with something fresh and interesting, being a fervent scholar of the philosophical theories, I went for the book by  Jim Proser ,  The Savage Messiah , an almost memoir-like, novel themed appraisal of the life of  Jordan B Peterson .

Saturday, April 11, 2020

Devotional: IF YOU WANT TO LEARN, BE HUMBLE

Poem of the Day: In Time of ‘The Breaking of Nations’ by Thomas Hardy

Entries:

         I need to work on focus, especially during work.

          Cultural inventions vary widely in their sophistication from society to society; within a society, the inventions are generally at the same level of sophistication . This is an allusion to the current disposition I am in after the continuous disintegrating of methodological states of being. In all these, I remain functional and progressive, an affirmation of the statement above; my culture being alien.

         You don’t win without taking a beating.

          . . . was to see if his neural systems could be shaped by patterned, repetitive experience in a safe and predictable environment .

         An excerpt from a reading of Al Hirschfeld daily rituals “ Very often, when an assignment is difficult, he can’t fall asleep until the artistic problem is solved, or he dreams about various ways of designing his drawing,” she wrote in 1999. “Now that’s what I call a hard worker! Even his subconscious doesn’t give him any time off. The next morning, holding onto that dream, he rises at first light and races to his drawing board to jot down all those nocturnal notions.  ”

Monday, April 13, 2020

Devotional: LESS IS MORE

Poem of the Day: The Song of Wandering Aengus by W. B. Yeats

Entries:

         An excerpt from today’s reading of the Stoic Devotional:  the writers we admire tend to be masters of economy and brevity. What they leave out is just as important—sometimes more important—than what they leave in. There is a poem by Philip Levine titled “He Would Never Use One Word Where None Would Do.”  A necessary wisdom for my journey into the literary world.

         The silver apples of the moon, the golden apples of the sun.

         How quickly it has been, since quitting my job, coming home, the switch from the promise of life to the pains of life, it’s been what? Two years now, and the miserableness of existence has pined at the peak of belief in a transcendental being of adoration.

         Thinking back to the times of the  Folly  incident, the “professor” who really isn’t a professor. I think I’ll write a story on this instead of just making it an input in my journal.

         The concept of “okuigbe” the word that depicts or means  dead shit  can be contrasted with the concept introduced by a colleague,  Osho  when he said:  they are the sick one’s, they don’t smoke . I won’t suffice, so I’m  dead shit  like:  he doesn’t smoke so he is sick .

         An excerpt from a course book I currently use:  I use the word “daimon” in its classic sense, referring to a kind of psychic twin—a motivating presence that first appears in one’s youth as a core image or experience that will come to animate, guide, and inform the individual throughout her life.

         Another excerpt:  Compensation Theory argues that the drive to flourish is grounded in childhood, adolescent, or early adulthood experiences of loss, deprivation, humiliation, scorn, bullying, abandonment, loneliness, and so on. Poverty inspires a need for security, shame a need to prove the mockers wrong, abandonment a need for trustworthy love—or safe, reliable solitude .

         Embrace the consistent cruelty, the “ everyday sadism ”. In it remain poised, focused, and unperturbed, for an individual who sees no evil in his actions is capable of virtually anything.

         I discovered the  Man Booker Prize  today. Now that’s the goal.

Tuesday, April 14, 2020

Devotional: BECOMING AN EXPERT IN WHAT MATTERS

Poem of the Day: The Woods and Banks by W. H. Davies

Entries:

         I see my dad first, while seeing unconditionally. Beautiful.

         Today, the cuckoo day, the most famous sound alarm clocks make. Just by the knowledge of this, I learn every day from my daily poem listening and stoic devotionals. Like how today’s input is about actually knowing what matters in life and giving it attention.

         An excerpt from a book I skimmed through Creating Characters: How to Build Story People:  In essence, boredom, I discovered (though it’s hardly a tremendous or unique insight), is a conflict state, in which duty, conditioning, or some other element demands you do one thing, when consciously or otherwise, you want to be doing something else.

         Excerpt from the fore-mentioned book, touching on the recent drop in output in my musical compositions:  The well, of course, is your own head. Your brain. Your consciousness. Your imagination. You’ve drained it of things that interest and intrigue you. Or, to put it another way, you’ve used the same story elements too often: the same ideas, the same settings, the same twists and complications, the same characters.

         Avoiding circumlocution is a dream, it’s been my reason for keeping a dictionary, and another reason for imposing on myself the daily write-ups in my journal.

         John Herschel Glenn Jr. Made the first orbital rocket-powered flight by a United States astronaut in 1962; later in United States Senate (1921-).

Thursday, April 16, 2020

Devotional: OBSERVE CAUSE AND EFFECT

Poem of the Day: Will Ye No Come Back Again? by Carolina Oliphant, Lady Nairne

Entries:

         It makes sense to relieve myself of these words, words that evoke a sense of purpose. Taking up literary learning is still to this point the journey with raptures so intense I will to see it through.

         An excerpt from a reading of the Lexicon of Ayn Rand’s Objectivism discussing America’s libertarian stands: “ All previous systems had regarded man as a sacrificial means to the ends of others, and society as an end in itself, The United States regarded man as an end in himself, and society as a means to the peaceful, orderly, voluntary co-existence of individuals. All previous systems had held that man’s life belongs to society, that society can dispose of him in any way it pleases, and that any freedom he enjoys is his only by favour, by the permission of society, which may be revoked at any time. The United States held that man’s life is his by right (which means: by   moral principle   and by   his nature  ), that a right is the property of an individual, that society as such has no rights, and that the only   moral purpose   of a government is the   protection of individual rights  . ”

         “ America is the land of the uncommon man. It is the land where man is free to develop his genius—and to get its just rewards. It is the land where each man tries to develop whatever quality he may possess and to rise to whatever degree he can, great or modest. It is not the land where one glories or is taught to glory in one’s mediocrity.

          No self-respecting man in America is or thinks of himself as “little,” no matter how poor he may be. That, precisely, is the difference he-tween an American working man and a European serf. ”

         “ The social system based on and consonant with the   altruist morality   —with the code of self-sacrifice—is socialism, in all or any of its variants: fascism, Nazism, communism. All of them treat man as a sacrificial animal to be immolated for the benefit of the group, the tribe, the society, the state. Soviet Russia is the ultimate result, the final product, the full, consistent embodiment of the altruist morality in practice; it represents the only way that that morality can ever be practiced. ”

In my little time in the literary world, I’ve come to realize the only connection being shared with the  collective  the herd of “the clan” is  shared human experience .

         An excerpt from a swift read of Heroes and Heroines hints on the concept of collective unconscious “ Carl Jung theorized that humans have a   collective unconscious  , "deposits of the   constantly repeated experiences of humanity   ... a kind, of readiness to reproduce over and over again the same or similar   mythical ideas   ..." This shared memory of experiences has resulted in   a resonance of the concepts   of hero and heroine that transcends time, place and culture. Jung called these recurring personalities ARCHETYPES, from the Greek word archetypos, meaning "first of its kind." "

         An excerpt from a reading of the lexicon of Objectivism: “ Ancient Greece tore away the heavy shroud of mysticism woven for centuries in murky temples, and achieved, in three centuries, what Egypt had not dreamed of in thirty: a civilization that was essentially   pro-man   and   pro-life  . The achievements of the Greeks rested on their confidence in the power of man’s mind—the power of   reason  . For the first time, men sought to understand the causes of natural phenomena, and gradually replaced superstition with the beginnings of science. For the first time, men sought to guide their lives by the judgment of reason, instead of resorting exclusively to divine will and revelation.

          The Greeks built temples for their gods, but they conceived of their gods as   perfect human beings  , rejecting the cats, crocodiles and cow-headed monstrosities enshrined and worshiped by the Egyptians. Greek gods   personified abstractions   such as Beauty, Wisdom, Justice, Victory, which are   proper human values  . In the Greek religion, there was   no omnipotent mystical authority   and no organized priesthood. The Greek had only a vague idea of, and little interest in, an afterlife. ”

          It is quite true what Philosophy says: that   Life must be understood backwards  . But that makes one forget the other saying: that it must be lived forwards. The more one ponders this, the more it comes to mean that life in the temporal existence never becomes quite intelligible, precisely because at no moment can I find complete quiet to take the backward-looking position.

 —The Diary of Søren Kierkegaard

          A novel is a mirror that is carried along a road.

         A quote from the Upanishads: “ The gods love the obscure and hate the obvious ”

Sunday, April 19, 2020

Devotional: OUR SPHERE OF IMPULSES

Poem of the Day: Concord Hymn Ralph by Waldo Emerson

Entries:

         Today’s devotional draws on the importance of curtailing the impulses, serving the common good and acknowledging the universality of wisdom regardless of caste, an epithet every good leader should imbibe. In detail today’s devotion implores that in our lives—whether we’re experiencing great power or powerlessness—it’s critical to leave room for what may happen and keep the common good and the actual worth of things front and centre. And, above all, be willing to learn from anyone and everyone, regardless of their station in life.

         Lexington and Concord, the first battle of the American Revolution (April 19, 1775).

         Avoid people looking for confrontation, remember curtail your impulses. Not doing so forebodes destruction.

         So I realised I virtue signal a lot, well am sorry, I’ll do better.

         Madness is something rare in individuals, but in groups, parties, peoples, ages it is the rule.

Monday, April 20, 2020

Devotional: REAL GOOD IS SIMPLE

Poem of the Day: I Had a Dove by John Keats

Entries:

         Knowing how to deal with what you don’t know.

Lesson Bits:

         The GOOD that the Stoics advocate in place of coveting is wisdom, self-control, justice, courage. No one who achieves these quiet virtues experiences buyer’s remorse.

         An excerpt from a reading of  Sanity is Impossibility :  Human history of thousands of years of civilization and cultures has been documented evidence of how misplaced ingenuity of minority of humanity, especially in powerful leadership positions, has always ruled over this mass idealism of compassion to shove the human world to the brink of extinction, with conflicts, confusion and chaos ruling all milieus and lives in them. The current diminutive and enslaved status of singular wisdom of compassion in contemporary human world is foolproof evidence that   Sanity Is Impossibility   in contemporary world and collective life-living. Those who truly understood Reality, humbly accepted compassion as only wisdom and lived and died in peace and wellness. Compassion remains the only singular Possibility of Sanity, at personal levels, as at collective level, compassion has lost the chance to reinstate itself long-long back…!

         Arbitrary introspective reprimanding of the idea of evil is still alien in every way, I’m not in terms with the collective unconsciousness of how humans deteriorate to a point of atrocity involving a neighbour losing his sanity, if all humans are the same, based on the  natural instinctiveness , I am certain the only reason why I differ is because of my knowledge. An allusion to the second paragraph of my lesson bit.

         Life is impermanence, and I have a disease, one affecting my heart, I barely have enough to eat, or anything to wear, a sheer reflection of how much of my health I remain unaware of, in the event of my death been news, it won’t be of my life having been a waste, a world existed before I was born to it, it would go on, existing when am out of it; but not without a tint of my shade.

         Having thoughts of suicide . . . without understanding?  Why  is a reflection of the unanswered question: “why am I here now?”

         The 19th Century was a pinchbeck age of literature.

Wednesday, April 22, 2020

Devotional: THE MARKS OF A RATIONAL PERSON

Poem of the Day: The Woodspurge by Dante Gabriel Rossetti

Entries:

         Understanding that the recent Cyber-Attack of the last few months have been deliberate attempts at having my self-examination and self-awareness deterred through the constant halt of deliberate arbitrary self-introspection.

         Extending my bailiwick to include literature of the Victorian era, even though its regarded as the pinchbeck age of literature.

         Understanding the difference between primal, primitive, and classic is essential in understanding the necessary discernment in historic matters. A simple tip.

Lesson Bits:

         An excerpt from a reading of the book Breaking open the head:  The extension of the self was, I realized, a natural process, akin to the blossoming of a plant. While a plant extends toward the sun throughout its life, human beings evolve internally. We rise up and flourish, or become stunted, involuted, as we react to the forces that press against us. Our growth takes place in the invisible realm of our mental space, and the unreachable sun we rise toward is   knowledge   —of the self and the universe.

Friday, April 24, 2020

Devotional: A PRODUCTIVE USE FOR CONTEMPT

Poem of the Day: Incident of the French Camp by Robert Browning

Entries:

         I feel like I’ll be dying soon, I don’t know when, but I feel I will be going soon, you leave once, I’ll be leaving soon.

         An excerpt from today’s reading of the book Cult X, alluding the premise of the prime possibility of contempt being productive:  There’s no need to worry about this in your day-to-day life. Besides, it might all just be erroneous scientific conclusions. However, if you ever find yourself questioning your consciousness, thinking, “Maybe I’m not actually deciding anything,” or “Maybe I’m really just a spectator,” then the clashes within your ego, the fights, and wars, appear truly hilarious. You may be able to see your wallowing (and don’t worry, wallowing itself is a good thing!) from a different perspective. You could think to yourself, “Ah, my brain is upset again! This collection of atoms is such a pain!” And then one thing becomes clear: how unbelievably incredible the system of the brain that produces “consciousness” is. One hundred something million neurons working nonstop at unbelievable speeds and intensities. Any being with that sort of system of consciousness within itself is truly incredible. Without consciousness and “me,” the brain wouldn’t be able to grasp its own functioning. In other words, it’s the same as saying you are your brain. And when I say “you are your brain,” both “you” and “your brain” are unique.

Saturday, April 25, 2020

Devotional: THERE’S NOTHING WRONG WITH BEING WRONG

Poem of the Day: Robinson Crusoe’s Wise Sayings by Ian McMillan

Entries:

         Repetitiveness doesn’t breed progress, a personal observation through a self-willed state.

         Understanding  civil  implies environmental in certain context is cool.

         I love it when I think of the utter unimportance of living a life that isn’t worth living, and a muscle spasm reiterates in consensus. It’s the only reason I need for my second suicide attempt. I should a fix a date, probably before the Coronavirus, give myself a last:  what is on my mind .

         I choose not to bother or displease my existence by pondering any of the ephemeral thoughts suggested, carrying out the current task is all that is of importance.

         Concentrate on the effect of your actions on your well-being, not others.

         The day the story of the lonesome Robinson Crusoe is published by Daniel Defoe in 1719.

         Thinking to myself, the constant perturbation of my state of consciousness, the almost perishing of the concept of  me . To think that I come from a lineage of royalty, a supposed dignified, regal race, I doubt it.

         Reading the book  Breaking open the head  I come by this idea by R. Gordon Wasson : “ A prodigious expansion in Man’s memory must have been the gift that differentiated mankind from his predecessors, and I surmise that this expansion in memory led to a simultaneous growth in the gift of language, these two powers generating in man that self-consciousness which is the third of the triune traits that alone make man unique. . . . I am asking myself whether Soma could have possessed the power to spark what I have called these triune traits. ” it’s a surmise not a factual theory. Wasson later came to deplore the idea of psychedelia saying “ Although these fungi had produced all of the great philosophic visions of antiquity, he proclaimed they had no relevance to the modern world. ”

         I wish my problems were pellucid. I catch myself doing things the wrong way. I want to cry most times, but in the end to live is to know when to die I think.

         To think I came home as an act of convalesce, only to deteriorate to a state of almost madness is beyond sad I . . .

Sunday, April 26, 2020

Devotional: THINGS HAPPEN IN TRAINING

Poem of the Day: Into my Heart an Air that Kills by A. E. Housman

Entries:

         Here is a profound insight, two points of view. One from a school of thought, a way of living — Stoicism. And an evolutionary perspective of instinctive response integrated with mythological discernment. The latter from a lecture on the biblical series:  Introduction to the idea of God  by Professor Jordan B Peterson, the former from today’s stoic devotional.

         Nature is beautiful. intelligence; beauty with direction. The latter suggest the use of attention and language to confront things that most threaten us. “ If there are things that upset — chaotic, terrible, serpentine, monstrous underworld things that threaten — the best thing is to open your eyes, get your speech organized, and go out and confront the thing, and make the world out of it — cancel out the upsetting object .” My understanding of this view is the instinctive discernment of the archetypal problem using perceptual inference.

         The other suggest, I paraphrase: “ When your sparring partner scratches or head-butts you, you don’t then make a show of it, or protest, or view him with suspicion or as plotting against you. And yet you keep an eye on him, not as an enemy or with suspicion, but with a healthy avoidance. You should act this way with all things in life. We should give a pass to many things with our fellow trainees. For, as I’ve said, it’s possible to avoid without suspicion or hate.

          By seeing each day and each situation as a kind of training exercise, the stakes suddenly become a lot lower. The way you interpret your own mistakes and the mistakes of others is suddenly a lot more generous. It’s certainly a more resilient attitude than going around acting like the stakes of every encounter put the championship on the line.

          When you catch an elbow or an unfair blow today, shake off the pain and remind yourself: I’m learning. My sparring partner is learning too. This is practice for both of us—that’s all. I know a bit more about him or her, and from my reaction, they’re going to learn a little bit more about me too. ”

         These two perspectives enjoin us on modes of reaction, a dichotomy of perception and action. I seem to be not just a practicing stoic but a budding philosopher.

         Some quotes I found on a look-up of the name Vladimir Nabokov a Russian and American novelist, poet, translator, and entomologist:

 You can always count on a murderer for a fancy prose style.

 It was love at first sight, at last sight, at ever and ever sight.

 The breaking of a wave cannot explain the whole sea.

         Some quotes from Jacques Lacan

 What does it matter how many lovers you have if none of them gives you the universe?

 The knowledge that there is a part of the psychic functions that are out of conscious reach, we did not need to wait for Freud to know this!

 In other words, the man who is born into existence deals first with language; this is a given. He is even caught in it before his birth.

Monday, April 27, 2020

Devotional: TURN IT INSIDE OUT

Poem of the Day: o by the by by E. E. Cummings

Entries:

         Being with someone is like flying your dreams as you would fly a kite.

         Like today’s unconventional nonsensical poem, today’s devotional pits an opposing idea against perceptive inference, alluding a form of commonsensical cognition. The former an allusion to pleasure void of much reason, the latter an approach at disciplined perception through the unbiased thought.

         The question is what are thoughts?  The formation of opinions, especially as a philosophy or system of ideas, or the opinions so formed.  What drives opinion formation? Fore-knowledge? Primal stimulation? The dialectic?

         The wisdom in today’s devotional knowledge offering is the innuendo of thought that . . .

         Call the fire station before starting the fire.

Some quotes:

 The world is mud-luscious and puddle-wonderful.

 life's not a paragraph and death I think is no parenthesis

 It takes courage to grow up and become who you really are.

         Today’s devotional speaks volume on the discernment of situations, implying an adjacent perspective, away from the obvious putative, substituting this for an inverse view, a clearly interesting proposition.  Stoicism is about looking at things from every angle—and certain situations are easier to understand from different perspectives. In potentially negative situations, the objective, even superficial gaze might actually be superior. That view might let us see things clearly without diving too much into what they might represent or what might have caused them. In other situations, particularly those that involve something impressive or praiseworthy, another approach, like that of contemptuous expressions, is helpful. By examining situations from the inside out, we can be less daunted by them, less likely to be swayed by them.

          Dig into your fear of death or obscurity, and what will you find? Turn some fancy ceremony inside out and you’ll find—what?

Thursday, April 30, 2020

Devotional: WHAT IS IN KEEPING WITH YOUR CHARACTER?

Poem of the Day: Facing It by Yusef Komunyakaa

Entries:

         Today the 30th of April 1975, fourty-five years ago today, Sygone, the capital of South Vietnam was captured, and its allies — the United States — defeated by the Northern forces of Vietnam in an event known historically as the fall of the Sygone, ending the Vietnam war, a conflict which had raged on for nearly 20 years, ending more than 4 million lives. Today’s poem is drawn from the memorial of the Vietnamese veterans honouring the soldiers who lost their lives.

         Well the unimportant fact of my total music videos folder been 6.66GB, I’d also like to add the fact that the music video of Trevor Daniel with my manager in at the back reading a book, is almost like an allusion to the principle of the Buddhist when he speaks on how the enlightened stays focused on the world within, away from the back dance of Shiva, you get it?

Lesson Bits:

         From today’s devotional, this elucidation wraps the concept of what it means to be a stoic, further drawing on the piece, Desiderata by Max Ehrmann from the 28th . A clear cut out column of this year’s direction. It is easy to get wrapped up in our own opinions of things. It’s as if we’re adhering to invisible scripts—following instructions or patterns we don’t even understand. The more you question these scripts and the more you subject them to the rigorous test of your education, the more you’ll be your own compass. You’ll have convictions and thoughts that are your own and belong to no one else.

         Character is a powerful defence in a world that would love to be able to seduce you, buy you, tempt you, and change you. If you know what you believe and why you believe it, you’ll avoid poisonous relationships, toxic jobs, fair-weather friends, and any number of ills that afflict people who haven’t thought through their deepest concerns. That’s your education. That’s why you do this work.

Wednesday, August 5, 2020

Devotional: SILENCE IS STRENGTH

Poem of the Day: Meg Merrilies by John Keats

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Remembering

Today's Musical: CLARINET SONATA IN E FLAT MAJOR, OP. 167 1: ALLEGRETTO BY CAMILLE SAINT-SAËNS (1835–1921)

Entries:

         I am confounded, I don’t know why, most of my relationships in the past have been online ones; remote and it’s been fine all this time but this has me confused, lonely and distraught, my thoughts feel so public.

          The character of man is consciousness; and the character of consciousness is to consume, perpetually, . . . the man of mind must finally reduce himself knowingly to an endless refusal to be anything whatever . From a book called Monsieur Teste, it’s a great interesting book by the author Paul Valery, and I’ll be reading more from the author.

 Consciousness cannot entirely consume being and still continue to exist. It depends on being. Sensibility is its home, knowledge is its profession.

         This crossed my mind and explains my new growing into laziness, holding me back from writing. It’s a text from the same book:  it is always a “sacrifice of thought” to write it down; the very act of writing stops thought by making it dependent on words for its expression.  Here he speaks of the logbook of Mr Teste.

         Syncretism is a term meaning the combining of different beliefs, while blending practices of various schools of thought. The abolishment of all barriers, all classes, all exclusions. This explains the egg by Andy Weir. The story, the concept album Everybody by Logic is based on.

Friday, August 7, 2020

Devotional: PRAGMATIC AND PRINCIPLED

Poem of the Day: The Meadow Mouse by Theodore Roethke

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Tears

Today's Musical: IF YE LOVE ME BY THOMAS TALLIS (C. 1505–1585)

Entries:

         This is a note on the disambiguation of the terms law and principle in its use:  Technically, in sciences, laws are predictions that are true. In reality, these laws are better classified as principles, which are true most of the time. However, the term law has stuck with these principles because they were established so long ago. So we will continue to refer to them as laws, even though technically they are not scientific laws.

         From an article on Gestalt psychology:  Gestalt psychologists argued that these principles exist because the mind has an   innate disposition to perceive patterns in the stimulus   based on certain rules. These principles are organized into categories including:   Proximity  ,   Similarity  ,   Continuity  ,   Closure  ,   Common Region  , and   Connectedness  .  I’m breaking down the principle of continuity for lack of an innate understanding of its workings.  The law of continuity is a   heuristic principle   introduced by Gottfried Leibniz based on earlier work by Nicholas of Cusa and Johannes Kepler. It is the principle that "  whatever succeeds for the finite, also succeeds for the infinite  ". Kepler used The Law of Continuity to calculate the area of the circle by representing the latter as an infinite-sided polygon with infinitesimal sides, and adding the areas of infinitely-many triangles with infinitesimal bases. Leibniz used the principle to extend concepts such as arithmetic operations, from ordinary numbers to infinitesimals, laying the groundwork for infinitesimal calculus. A mathematical implementation of the law of continuity is provided by the transfer principle in the context of the hyperreal numbers. A related law of continuity concerning intersection numbers in geometry was promoted by Jean-Victor Poncelet in his "Traité des propriétés projectives des figures".

         Kindly note that some of these principles can sometimes lead to incorrect perceptions of the world. It is important to remember that while these principles are referred to as laws of perceptual organization, they are actually heuristics or short-cuts. Heuristics are usually designed for speed, which is why our perceptual systems sometimes make mistakes and we experience perceptual inaccuracies.

Saturday, August 8, 2020

Devotional: START WITH WHERE THE WORLD IS

Poem of the Day: from A Song About Myself by John Keats

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

The Detached

Today's Musical: DUET FOR TWO VIOLINS BY STEVE REICH (B. 1936)

Entries:

         Learning today that jealousy is a sort of moral emotion. Here is an excerpt of the note on skepticism:  Evolutionary psychologists have worked out the science behind the moral emotion of jealousy, which evolved as a motivation of behavior called mate guarding.

          Our moral sentiments—the moral emotions contained within our mental armory—seem to have evolved out of pre-moral feelings of our hominid, primate, and mammalian ancestors, the remnants of which can be found in modern apes, monkeys, and other big-brained mammals. These sentiments are considered to be pre-moral because morality involves right and wrong thoughts and behaviors in the context of a social group. It does not appear that other animals can consciously assess the rightness or wrongness of thoughts or actions in themselves or fellow members of their species.

          Anyone who has had a dog as a pet recognizes that dogs quickly learn the difference between right and wrong, feel some sense of shame or guilt when scolded for bad behavior, and express joy and pride when being praised for good behavior. That sense of shame or pride is what we mean by “moral sentiments”;   because dogs don’t have symbolic language or, presumably, cognition  , these are premoral sentiments.

         I just lost all my last input, it was on an article I had just read, my dad called me just after, I was getting his books. I switched my backup mode from smart to scheduled, I guess smart isn’t that smart, or some petty hack. Sucks, what is true or to be trusted? Nah I won’t be a cynic. Please help me if you hear me, I’m nice and don’t have evil plans. Just a regular young man trying to put food on the table.

         Here is an excerpt from an article by Massimo Pigliucci from https://evolution-institute.org

         It discusses the subject of morality being universal or not, and touches on the philosophical school of Stoicism and how it offers a pragmatic way of living.

           Socrates, the Stoics, the Epicureans, the Cynics, and a number of other Greco-Roman schools agreed on one thing: human beings are a particular type of animal, and that particularity lies chiefly in two aspects of what it means to be human: we are   highly social  , and we are   capable of reason  .

           The first bit means that   we are all deeply inter-dependent on other people  . Despite the fashionable nonsense, especially in the United States, about “self-made men” (they are usually men), there actually is no such thing. Without social bonds and support our lives would be, as Thomas Hobbes famously put it, poor, nasty, brutish, and short. The second bit, the one about intelligence, does not mean that we always, or even often, act rationally. Only that   we have the capability to do so  .

          Ethics, then, especially (but not only) for the Stoics becomes a matter of “  living according to nature  ,” meaning not to endorse whatever is natural (that’s an elementary logical fallacy), but rather t  o take seriously the two pillars of human nature  :   sociality   and   reason  . As Marcus Aurelius put it, “Do what is necessary, and whatever the reason of a social animal naturally requires, and as it requires.” (Meditations, IV.24)

           There is something, of course, the ancients did get wrong: they, especially Aristotle, thought that   human nature was the result of a teleological process  , that everything has a proper function, determined by the very nature of the cosmos. We don’t believe that anymore, not after Copernicus and especially Darwin. But we do know that   human beings are indeed a particular product of complex and ongoing evolutionary processes  . These processes do not determine a human essence, but they do   shape a statistical cluster of characters that define what it means to be human  . That cluster, in turn,   constrains   —   without determining   — what sort of behaviors are pro-social and lead to human flourishing, and what sort of behaviors don’t. And ethics is the empirically informed philosophical enterprise that attempts to understand and articulate that distinction.

Friday, August 14, 2020

Devotional: THIS ISN’T FOR FUN. IT’S FOR LIFE

Poem of the Day: from Macbeth by William Shakespeare

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Let's Majeste

Entries:

         The only thing that matters now is me getting it right. I wake up twenty-five minutes ago with lingering night visions, I’m in a trap-house smoking hard drugs, It’s a very hostile environment. The dream isn’t very vivid, far from eidetic, but there are fragments of images left, I’ll be recording them in the  night vision  bar. I haven’t recorded any in a while now, it’s strictly a thing of laziness, as I have stopped smoking weed—nothing holding me back—making them commonplace in my mornings.

         It’s a sad narrative, what my life will be if I don’t take charge of my story, I have been away from my journal, and my daily rituals, only having access to my devotional through a mobile phone, a device with enough problems of its own. The reason for this input is to draw attention to the last day’s entry; a poem from Maya Angelou, where I mistook the title of  Accident  for  Tonight .

         The word  accident  has been used on several occasions to describe the psychological phenomenon of psychosis, this being a repetitive occurrence in the constant jabberwocky assault. I have chosen not to record any of it in my journal as the nomenclature of the “game-mind” is something I have chosen not to dabble with as I thought it was unnecessary. Moving forward I think in my leisure time, I’ll be doing a disambiguation of the terms, stating clearly what I infer from the commonly used words, phrases and even some of the concepts and what I should, saving my cognition any hampering to its workings. I must admit in shame that I wish not to take on this.

         Drawing from the last input, my words on the nomenclature of the perceived “game-mind”. The word  Ajebutter  and its origin, based on what I know from a google search; it meaning a brand of butter sold to the  elite  and also what it stands for now: a superior race or class of Yorubas. Ah, so funny. To me, all I see it as, is a weak way of hiding the frailty of the inability of a people to deal with their insecurities, their shortcomings, an almost waning whine of defeat at something so rudimentary and important. It begs the question: what makes for a civilized society?

         I despise my choice of words and attempts at marshalling my train of thoughts. I have been away too long from journaling, it has affected my spewing, my dexterity, my austerity, my formality and audacity, crippling my eloquent demeanour of perceived “ compelling ”.

         Will it take my own death to be cognizant of my own life, my life as a whole?

         Jessica posted a song it’s called May 1st by Beach Fossils, after listening I decided to search for a song of May 23rd since May 1st is hers. It returned a couple of results and I went with the first entry in the song bar, it was a piano  fingering . After listening, I scrolled down and found a podcast entry in its section, I decided to look it up as its name is interesting, it’s titled The Left Right Game.

Downloading and listening, as I have just started, barely three full minutes in as I type in this entry, it starts with an auto-crash of the protagonist, I guess. He is bedridden, his doctor comes in as he’d been out up until now. He’s taking notes and he ask what day it is . . . It’s  Friday, erm . . .  It’s Friday today and I didn’t know it was Thursday up until late yesterday night. Another thing of interest is my last tweet, on which says Tawny and Beige no archives @itsjessandrea <put smiling face smiley here>. Next thing I’m on Charli XCX’s Instagram page and it’s the day—Thursday—she’s having her Live remote show and it’s no archives—she isn’t archiving, no replays fam— and the first clip on her story’s timeline is from a fan, some  Beigesandal . Okay . . . I’m not into Pythagorean and all but hey! That hella makes me feel good . . . oh, oh not forgetting that In my freestyle the one I sent to Jessica last, where I discovered the phrase “keep unlocking my beige”, there is another where I say “why I gotta go out of my way just to let you feel how I feel.” Her latest album she threw a listening party for—How I’m feeling now. And the cream to the coffee . . . Yes, the  protagonist  had an accident, the last poem form Maya Angelou in my daily entry is  accident . The one mistaken for tonight. It’s all a bit vague but it’s a fine ball of strings.

         An excerpt from my reading of today of the course on Skepticism: In his book Immortality:  The Quest to Live Forever and How It Drives Civilization, the British philosopher Stephen Cave calls this the mortality paradox: “Death presents itself as both inevitable and impossible,” he suggests. We see it all around us, yet “it involves the end of consciousness, and we cannot consciously simulate what it is like to not be conscious.”  isn’t life a beautiful paradox. An almost wanton enigma, depends on where you look at it from.

         Another excerpt paraphrased is:  Given that our normal experience is of stimuli coming into the brain from the outside, when a part of the brain abnormally generates hallucinations caused by another part of the brain; low activity in the posterior superior parietal lobe, a region of the brain authors have dubbed the orientation association area (OAA) —quite possibly the left-hemisphere interpreter described by neuroscientist Michael Gazzaniga—interprets them as external events. Hence, the abnormal is interpreted as supernormal.

          A final piece of evidence comes from research by neuroscientists who have now documented that in the brains of people undergoing hallucinations, the same sensory perceptual systems become active

 as those engaged in the sensation of actual physical stimulation. As the great neurologist Dr. Oliver Sacks notes in his many remarkable books, all such experiences reside in the brain, not in the world.

 Belief in the afterlife is a type of dualism. Because we are natural-born dualists who intuitively believe that our minds are separate from our brains and bodies, the afterlife is the logical step in projecting our own mind-agency into the future without our bodies.

         An excerpt from the last chapter:  Even with all these precautions in place, any of us may end up believing weird things, even while being rational and scientific in other areas of our lives. The reason for this has to do with what we might call logic-tight compartments—modules in the brain analogous to watertight compartments in a ship. The existence of compartmentalized brain functions, acting in either concert or conflict, has been a core idea of evolutionary psychology since the 1990s. According to University of Pennsylvania evolutionary psychologist Robert Kurzban, the brain evolved as a modular, multitasking, problem-solving organ—a Swiss army knife of practical tools. There is no unified “self” that generates internally consistent and seamlessly coherent beliefs. Instead, we are a collection of distinct but interacting modules that are often at odds with one another.

Some quotes:

Carl Sagan  Extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence.

Christopher Hitchens  What can be asserted without evidence can also be dismissed without evidence.

David Hume’s  A wise man proportions his belief to the evidence.

Skeptic Motto  I don’t know.” We don’t have to have an explanation for everything.

Isaac Asimov  When people thought the Earth was flat, they were wrong. When people thought the Earth was spherical, they were wrong. But if you think that thinking the Earth is spherical is just as wrong as thinking the Earth is flat, then your view is wronger than both of them put together.

Richard Dawkins  When two opposite points of view are expressed with equal intensity, the truth does not necessarily lie exactly halfway between them. It is possible for one side to be simply wrong.

Timothy Ferris  The founders often spoke of the new nation as an ‘experiment.’ Procedurally, it involved deliberations about how to facilitate both liberty and order, matters about which the individual states experimented considerably during the eleven years between the Declaration of Independence and the Constitution . . . Ferris sees political claims, such as the idea of equality under the

 law, as “methods, not ideologies.” Both [liberalism and science] incorporate feedback loops through which actions (e.g., laws) can be evaluated to see whether they continue to meet with general approval. Neither science nor liberalism makes any doctrinaire claims beyond the efficacy of its respective methods—that is, that science obtains knowledge and that liberalism produces social orders generally acceptable to free peoples.”

Albert Einstein  One thing I have learned in a long life: that all our science, measured against reality, is primitive and childlike—and yet it is the most precious thing we have.

Night Visions:

         Well, I was in a trap house, I can’t remember what I was doing there but I was with some males, I can’t remember any known face, or make-out any. It’s the normal spirit in the air, the same theme of all my previous, or better said, my recent last visits to the trap house; “the lack of resource”, “inability to pacify cravings” not on my end at least. My last visits have been more of “reasons not to come around”, “why it’s definite, my quitting”. Derailing from the vision, it’s now a known fact, at least from recent reactions, that my visits to places like Ota stir up visions of drug use in my dreams, this solely being that my only reason for going there have been to get drugs, now my street is filled with drug addicts, even if I don’t see them doing it, I know better, besides my initials read O.T.A, that is Ogundipe Theophilus Ademola. I should know the town well you would think.

         Continuing my vision, I’m in the trap-house and I turn out a new “product”, I unwrap it and it’s big, almost too big—it’s a dream so I guess it all makes sense— I’m thinking to myself as I write this how alive I am. Fuck, it’s so surreal and I miss Jessica, I don’t know words to say to her but I want to shout it out that I love her, and I will next time I’m online, even if it sounds stupid. Back to the night vision, a whole paragraph wasted.

         Okay, so I turn it out and I’m really selfish with it, all these boys want it more than I do, ready to roll heads. Well, I wasn’t allowed to smoke it on dividing it, I give half to someone—I think—and I try smoking the other, but I receive a pinch to my back and it all became a joke, like hey why am I being so selfish with this, it isn’t even worth anything, just another way of destroying this good God giving life.

Tuesday, August 18, 2020

Devotional: ONLY FOOLS RUSH IN

Poem of the Day: Don’t Let That Horse by Lawrence Ferlinghetti

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Mourning Grace

Today's Musical: SYMPHONY NO. 35 IN D MAJOR, K. 385 (‘HAFFNER’) 1: ALLEGRO CON SPIRITO BY WOLFGANG AMADEUS MOZART (1756–1791)

Entries:

         Wiayu was just one of several minnows of the underground incubation stage startups in Nigeria.

My thinking affects how I feel, which in turn affects my behaviour. I should never forget my discretion. The choice to not do what I want to do is what amounts to fear and confusion coming in. Jessica is carrying me along, promising not to ever let me go. I love her for she’s not only herself, she’s helped me be myself back. I’m so tapped into what matters to me right now, no one outside of me has the ability or right to tell me what is right for me. I’m done sacrificing that choice to anyone else. No one is more important in my life than me. I will honour my own commitment to my own dreams first and foremost giving my 100% of me; self, the version of me that is in alignment with what I desire. Nothing is being done to me, everything is being done by me. I’m free, one thought, one feeling, one choice at a time of what to give my priceless focus to. My days begin to take on a new form of energy, a new sort of quality, saying yes to things that energize me and begin to politely and firmly decline things that take energy from me. My days begin to shift, morph, and become a clearer more accurate representation of my own purpose, path, and plan.

Now all that is left is for me to enjoy this feeling, this remembrance of my own power; always there, every second, breath, heartbeat, my power to choose remains.

 Cull from Jesse Elder’ Podcast -- Creating Time Abundance

         I hope to always remain with a vantage point that is incisive and objective.

         An excerpt from my current reading of the article: Animal cognition, it explains the idea of the common remark of the game-mind:  Parastitch , simply translated as “he can’t be any different, that’s his permanent state.”

          For example, when monkeys watched as two eggplants were placed behind a screen, they looked longer when the screen was removed and only one eggplant was present than when two eggplants were present. Monkeys may have spent more time looking at the incorrect outcome because it surprisingly violated the rules of arithmetic. But, the results of such studies may be explained in terms of the infants’ and monkeys’   understanding of object permanence  : organisms can keep track of   occluded objects   and when one object unexpectedly appears or disappears, they are surprised; no real arithmetic ability is required in that case.  Now who is stunned and mortified?

         Primacy and recency are two serial position effects—contingents—in memory formation and retention.

Wednesday, August 19, 2020

Devotional: CORRALLING THE UNNECESSARY

Poem of the Day: Prologue by Patience Agbabi

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Changing

Entries:

         Isn’t this what life is? A tad bit off normalcy, and all together weird. Well, I was listening to the Anthropocene podcast by John Green, the episode been  Indianapolis and Love at first sight , and I must say I learned some of what the real—in quote—American life is like, Indianapolis being a model state or instance of this. What’s driven for this post is the pellucid serendipity—actually the two listeners who sent a mail, requesting to have these subjects reviewed; that is: Indianapolis, and Love at first sight. Listening to the first topic in reviewal, I could not but try to ebb back my thoughts from cascading in a domino of plausible events in the life of I and my love. Him talking about his lawn, and I thinking of my dread for laborious activities, but not willing to pass the buck if it means losing my girl. Yes, I know it’s a bit tripe, but enough of that. What’s mind boggling here is the fact that Indianapolis was suggested by Jessie, and love at first sight was suggested by Theo, huh? Jessie and Theo, really that’s some oddity, of all episodes, of all names? Okay, I guess I’m growing, I’m hearing voices, and now the world is some beautiful odyssey where I get my girl and we live forever after if I make the right choices. Great, I guess God isn’t so tyrant after all. What do you think? lol.

         I posted a freestyle, sent it to Jessica, it’s named shitFreestyle on my computer, but it’s renamed “how vulnerable Jess” in my Google cloud drive.

Author's Note

         A lot strikes a man as important, and poignant during his lifetime. When I was a kid, it was my female desk partner in the classroom who stroked my thighs a lot. We sat in the front row, she wore a very short gown, refused to recite the national anthem on the morning assembly ground, and her excuses? For the gown, her parents couldn’t afford to replace her old, now skimpy ones. And as to her indifference to the patriotic solemnity? She threw it out as incompatible with her religious faith, she was a Jehovah Witness, and I was seven years old. I didn’t get it; prescription was all I knew. Publications like The Watchtower and Awake! helped me growing up. They were my major source of information about the international world, grew my love for nature, and science, and brought to my hands, exemplars in the local scene doing Jehovah’s work.

         It kept on happening, she touched me for pleasure, just my thighs, but I never touched her. Her chocolate brown skin, lissom neck, slit eyes, and calming voice were just that; of a soon-to-be-replaced desk mate. I once suffered a mean male mate; he stabbed my palm with a pencil. It is a hotchpotch of history from a time Leonor, Princess of Asturias was still to be birth, amazing titbit.

         My teenage years made me understand I needed more ways to navigate life. With my grandma visiting, and mum seeing her off, I was distracted from a sentimental bye to her, with a call to the environment, of how it could use some cleaning. In some hurry or sheer uninterest, I informed her, the outdoor broom was missing, it undoubtedly was, and it usually didn't take a long search to find it. She at the instance, convinced me it wasn’t a bad idea to use the indoor one to get the chore completed. I did and faced the music, nothing less, I got punished, and it stuck. For me, it was high-up injustice. I followed the instructions given and cleaned the ground. I’m happy to fill the dark and unnoticed, the bristles were soft and it made the chore a breeze.

         I just hated that I couldn’t talk to anyone, the elders were mean and did whatever pleased them, and there wasn’t a sure way to track the importance of antecedence. Nothing made much sense so I turned to text, good ones always gave the hand of friendship, and it wasn’t much of playing with the older, when I told my biological dad, one day on a drive to my university, I was sixteen, that I find it hard to commit to mind, things I can’t grasp structurally. I can’t cram, he thought I meant

         At twenty-one, when weed got hip, I'd had friends who enjoyed it when I was eighteen, but they were friends because we shared the same university hall. Smoke up my lungs at the time, felt too far removed from the boy who watched that one man in the recreation club, who is friends with my biological dad, who'd fling cigarettes’ butts without a stub. I’d watch him, pick it up, go into the dark, and pray for a glow. I never got one, or maybe it was the dispelling tobacco smell. The ash also was unpleasant. But I had a man who helped in menial jobs, whose son came around a couple of times, to help put me out of my misery. He came with nothing but left with a good smoke. A paper and a matchbox, that was all, we smoked paper, but it didn’t leave me still wanting to smoke, I coughed, there was too much smoke, and the desire had met its satiety.

         So twenty-one, I ingested a lot of weed, still frowning at inhaling smoke. When I did, it was uneventful, but for pictures and the pipe used, and my Armani shirt. It was lacklustre, my best days of high were behind me, but I smoked a lot from then on.

         Losing sense of my table, and drifting for a brief moment. Having just looked back through the stack of files I had recently updated to make sense of the last written line of code, coming to hate the distraction the substance provided in parallel suggestions, I knew it was time to call it quits. I did, and in less than three months, got the job on my hands completed. I enjoyed being sober for a while, and started a mixtape, and swore to never go back to my habitual weed smoking, and since I had smoked crack-cocaine a couple of times, and to be very certain I would be going through with this clean episode of efficaciousness, and abstinence, on the mixtape, I declared and presented myself as a habitual drug user in recovery. It helped me, because it took me off of everyone’s radar. Somehow, their eyes weren’t the judging ends, very few would be aware of whatever was happening in my life, only close associates, friends, and family.

         Before my declaration, I had become friends with Brian Rose, the host of London Real on Facebook. I sent him a cover of a song I had made, Moonlight by XXXTentacion. He thought the beat was nice. I was very unimpressed at his only admiration for the beat. Weeks earlier, he had encouraged me, along with a group to record a video introduction presenting ourselves, he said it would put us in a position of accountability. I saw a few faces in the group and gave up. Oh, I couldn’t do this. Another time, in a live-video class, he offered to break down my business, a music-streaming platform, as an example for the class, so I went offline. Oh, it was just a bore, I won't be able to take the information in, I told myself. They were actual human beings, I'd need to sell my products to, but my self-confidence was in tatters.

         Something had to change, I had to understand what I was doing smoking weed every night, all mornings before nine, and in between breaks when finally, I had the office all to myself. I remember telling the drug dealer I needed something stronger, a more potent strain I had told him. I could afford a better drug if it was what I wanted, but it wasn’t. I was a lonely busy young man, on an uphill battle for a steady income, with problems very personal, as writing a software program, which only shows up more holes to fit, needing a change in the blueprint.

         When I told the drug dealer, I’d smoked crack a couple of times, he told me he took sleeping pills in the past, but thanks to his mum, he only smokes weed and drinks beer now, as it almost ruined him. His girlfriend could help me get some was his response, he called me a professor, admired me, and told me to avoid crack, but not in any way alarming. It is fine to say he didn’t directly, but through allusion, I guess a silence pervaded the place in abjection, whispering the obvious. I left that town still owing him, we met shortly after the debt but never discussed it, only I knew I had to pay him. I had gotten more money than usual one night from a client and he threw his weight in, helping with a filler sum for the supply to counteract my frozen bank account.

         A sort of race had started, I was either racing to penance or handshakes from the real users. I discovered the dealer’s delivery man had been ripping me off and followed him to the drug house, it is there some well-dressed fellow shook my hand like I had just ruined my life, depending on how you look at it. It hurt back in my well lit, clean office. My use lasted for a few days because I smoked a lot at once. When the month ended, the first month of relapse, with a track on the mixtape reading Better off the drugs, it was clear what the news was, I was about to become an addict.

         I resigned at the end of the month, said no to opportunities that would keep my pocket fat, and moved back home. Back with my biological parents, I donned rags instead of casual clothing. There was a shame I couldn’t blot off, and I needed someone to talk to me. I spoke to myself, read books, and took myself more seriously. Started a journal, and partook in compulsory morning rituals. Soon I was clean finally, the year is 2020, my year of growth. Several times I had typed the letters, Vision2020 in the password box, pondering its other significance, outside of my knowledge of its pop reference to Justin Timberlake’s album, and visual acuity. The year was 2017, I had no plans for the year outside of my job, but I desperately wanted a life worth living, so to speak, another password. The real sobriety battle started August 31, 2018 after my resignation.

         My road to writing poetry fills these pages. I somewhere found my voice again. I share this journal as it is, to show the other sap I live through. It is self-improvement. There are personal notes and recorded knowledge from my numerous readings. They’ve brought me this far, nothing compares to the personal time, we spend with ourselves. I am glad I had these special moments recorded.

         2019, was a tough year, another relapse worse than I could imagine, it lasted a few days, less than two weeks, and it taught me something. A familiar voice finally started speaking. But it had not brought an intervention, it dismissed philosophy in a fashion dissimilar to ignorance, as not the answer, to acquaint with heroin. It seemed to suggest madness. The actions that led to this journal saved me. In my head was some other friend who fought to live as my activities grew and so did my knowledge, helping him rest easy.

Thursday, December 24, 2020

Devotional: MEANINGLESS . . . LIKE A FINE WINE

Entries:

         Excerpts from the book Reasons to stay alive:

 There is this idea that you either read to escape or you read to find yourself. I don’t really see the difference. We find ourselves through the process of escaping. It is not where we are, but where we want to go, and all that. ‘Is there no way out of the mind?’ Sylvia Path famously asked. I had been interested in this question (what it meant, what the answers might be) ever since I had come across it as a teenager in a book of quotations. If there is a way out, a way that isn’t death itself, then the exit route is through words. But rather than leave the mind entirely, words help us leave a mind, and give us the building blocks to build another one, similar but better, nearby to the old one but with firmer foundations, and very often a better view.

 So the fact that this book exists is proof that depression lies. Depression makes you think things that are wrong.

 I know, I know, we are humans. We are a clandestine species. Unlike other animals we wear clothes and do our procreating behind closed doors. And we are ashamed when things go wrong with us. But we’ll grow out of this, and the way we’ll do it is by speaking about it. And maybe even through reading and writing about it.

 Depression looks different to everyone. Pain is felt in different ways, to different degrees, and provokes different responses. That said, if books had to replicate our exact experience of the world to be useful, the only books worth reading would be written by ourselves.

 Unlike a book or a film depression doesn’t have to be about something.

 It is said that insanity is a logical response to an insane world. Maybe depression is in part simply a response to a life we don’t really understand. Of course, no one understands their life completely if they think about it. An annoying thing about depression is that thinking about life is inevitable. Depression makes thinkers out of all of us. Just ask Abraham Lincoln.

 Hovering over what? According to Albert Camus, is the only serious question human beings have to deal with.

 Fear makes us curious. Sadness makes us philosophise.

 To be calm becomes a kind of revolutionary act. To be happy with your own non-upgraded existence.

 Life lesson: the way out is never through yourself.

 Sometimes on the rocky, windy path of recovery, what feels like failure can be a step forward.

 Do you not see how necessary a world of pains and troubles is to school an intelligence and make it a soul?

 You need to feel life’s terror to feel its wonder.

 … and I am glad for the synesthesia that means when I read Emily Dickinson or Mark Twain my mind feels actual warmth from those old American words.

 How to stop time: kiss.

 How to travel in time: read.

 How to escape time: music.

 How to feel time: write.

 How to release time: breathe.

Saturday, February 8, 2020

Devotional: DID THAT MAKE YOU FEEL BETTER?

Poem of the Day: An Unusual Cat-Poem by Wendy Cope

Entries:

         Today is a beautiful day, woke up feeling great, I’ll be doing meditation today, getting the gear was easy, I stole an improvised mat from the kitchen turned store in my apartment, it’s kept, not in lock; in my wardrobe. I will be starting a course by Sam Harris; it’s called  Waking up with Sam Harris.  I can’t wait to start.

         Starting the program, really interesting, I discovered a technique of meditation, twice now. First, in a book by Yuval Noah Harari; 21 lessons of the 21st century, and now, in the course by Sam Harris, it’s called  Vipassana , it’s translated as  insight  ,  gotten from the Buddhism school of  Theravada . The Theravada is said to be the oldest tradition of Buddhism, and the quality of mind to be cultivated, attained, is mindfulness.

         I had a dream, we were kids, got married under a mango tree, kissed and turned to fairies. I had an idea come to me, I’ll put my joy in breaking things, the climax of this, being my bachelor night; breaking plates, cups, all that gives a smash sound, till it pops a joint or lose interest out of sheer fatigue.

         In an age, where all everyone cares about, is narcissism, hence the reason I’m interested in my story. Heather Mac Donald has won my heart, the part that’s mad at close female acquaintances, who’ve chosen to bank their existence on entitlements. I’ll refute all sexist claims, each has been given a cross to bear.

Night Visions:

         Can’t remember much, all I can is, I was in a hotel room, I presume, from memories of familiar spaces, a room with a transparent backdrop of glass wall. Outside, just past the adjacent road, is a field, memories of the field spark emotions of Baby Goth’s 2019 performance spaces.

Sunday, February 9, 2020

Devotional: YOU DON’T HAVE TO HAVE AN OPINION

Poem of the Day: It Was Long Ago by Eleanor Farjeon

Entries:

         8:20 A.M it’s a beautiful day, and I am learning, listened to a lecture, a synopsis on the tales of Gilgamesh. I’ll be giving it a second listen. From the poem of today by Eleanor Farjeon, I learned that poems are for memorizing as well as for memorializing. Makes me ponder what I’ll be memorizing and memorializing in any poem I’ll be writing soon, probably of the love of years past?

         Listening in on the audiobook by Grant Cardone, “Be obsessed or be average”. I’m reminded on the lesson from months back, there is something, to refreshing your mind, just as the bible says, the constant washing of the feet; the symbolism for reminding yourself. There is also something, to reading your own words, as said by Jordan B Peterson in a discourse with him, and Heather Mac Donald, on what the higher in higher education means.

         Coming in to this house, my father’s property, one where I spent a lot of years growing up, it’s suddenly reminded me, of how important mental health is, and how easy it is to lose the band. It’s sad, seeing people, full blown sick, being dangerous, not to themselves alone, but to their immediate environment, and people in it.

         The washing of the feet is a wake-up call, haters will be haters. They are the fuel I need for my next level; Jesse Elder says haters aren’t to be given any attention, and you don’t need them. He has an approach to handling them, mine being the aphorism from today’s devotional, “You Don’t Have to Have an Opinion”. The only problem: handling naysayers, the one’s closest, people with the highest affinity at afflicting damage.

Tuesday, February 11, 2020

Devotional: HERO OR NERO?

Poem of the Day: The Missile by Michael Leunig

Entries:

         Writing this, listening to my old freestyle, saved by the name Juice, it’s interesting knowing how much has changed since then, it’s funny how peace is fleeting, I know one thing as much, peace isn’t relative, to think of it in such term is to constantly put yourself under a radar of constant comparison, stealing the joy of the moment. It’s 5:58 AM.

         I’m starting a course on scepticism today, same day, my dad tells me I’ll be visiting a witch doctor. Apparently, my life has being going, not so impressive, as he’d like it to go. I’ll be having a tongue-in-cheek attitude towards it. A week from now I guess I’ll be in this man’s presence. What are the thoughts I’ll be entertaining, and what suggestions would the surrounding enclave of mystic shenanigans offer? Maybe bones of dead sapiens, I bet they can’t summon the balls to entertain their guest with such bizarreness. Anyway it goes I’ll be having a good one, it’s not my first time being tricked to believe in some mystic phenomenon.

I will be starting my day now, just saw the first episode of Rugrats, haven’t seen it all, going great, will probably see it again, I was munching away while watching so I was kind of divided between my sweet tooth and my cliché childhood nostalgic flight.

         It’s 12:01 AM and I’m listening to  My Birthday by Anne Marie , great song, started the lecture on The Bhagavid Gita, no it should be Bhagavad Gita, yes I got it after looking it up.

         It’s 3:32 PM, sipping from the perennial knowledge fountain of the great ones, I found a great nugget I’d like to deposit here.

Lesson Bits:

         An excerpt from today’s poem, quote  “It’s modern warfare’s answer to an ancient wisdom trialed and true, when fighting wars, you first destroy all songs of innocence and joy.”

         Acting from Karma-Yoga; not getting attached to the fruits. According to the Bhagavad Vita, your action becomes more effective. Krishna says: “thinking  of objects, attachment is formed in the mind, from attachment, longing, and from longing anger grows. From anger, comes delusion, and from delusion, loss of memory, and from loss of memory, comes the ruin of understanding, from the ruin of understanding, man perishes .” But if you can act in accordance with Karma-Yoga, you’ll be at peace.

          “But the self-controlled man, moving among objects with senses under restraint, free from attraction and aversion, attains the tranquility.”

         Krishna says  “He whose mind is not shaken by adversity, who does not hanker after happiness, who is become free from affection, fear, and wrath is indeed the sage of steady wisdom.”  What a lovely image to be the sage of steady wisdom, calm, unperturbed, regardless of what might come.

Wednesday, February 12, 2020

Devotional: PROTECT YOUR PEACE OF MIND

Poem of the Day: Lift Every Voice and Sing by James Weldon Johnson

Entries:

         It’s 8:16 AM, not really happy, I don’t know where I am, feels like I woke up in a bad dream, something is for sure amiss, I’ll brace this little heart of mine, forage on the little wisdom I find and forge on.

         What would I sell my freedom for, I’ll trade in my life for my freedom, just to get a chance . . . I’ll keep my perception tethered to you; truth. In a world of fallacy and lies, remaining devoted to a life of unperturbed tranquillity can only be sustained in a world where mind shape minds through the proper application of, discernment of objective reality. People with feasible tyrant traits like the immediate younger offspring, after my conception; delineating between alive and dead, living taking precedence, is a specimen for objective prodding. Understanding why siblings raised under the same living conditions, stray from the path of rationality to a cul-de-sac of mentally agitated existence, sprouting a decadence of personal, ethical harmony in nuclear relationships, and communal engagements.

Living is for the purposeful, to be purposeful is to seek change. To seek change is to have a nucleus of permanence, for change only comes as a morph, not as a replacement. In the understanding of human behaviour, the arrival at perceptions, shaped by conscious tinkering is central at arriving at the base-philosophy that guides ethical conduct.

         Listening to Anticlimax by Mae Muller, thinking, how lucky am I to have this song? Such irony! A perfect inverse misnomer on what’s happened, well; from the name of the song, the song itself being perfidious, at least in relation to the course of my initial posit narrative. I planned on keeping this pithy, but for some hypothetical telepathic phenomenon, I’m yet to laser on; sceptical about this, I will bow to no pseudo-science, I’m here ranting on about thoughts of little significance. Well, what I wanted to pen down is, it’s a beautiful time to be alive. Why? You may ask. Well, tens of centuries ago, my community of tribal bigots will have their ease on the edge, by the constant fear of raiders in thirst of victims’ blood. Maybe the times aren’t so provident, with constant flares of provocation, the one under the lens, being the anticlimax; my neighbour has chosen to live a life that encompasses not just her thoughts, but that of a foreign being, or maybe this computer is hacked like my previous, whichever way it goes, I’ll be in the heart of tranquillity, putting subliminal and outcries of raucous babel where they belong, in the thrash where nulled thoughts go.

         Social interaction involves reconciling different aspects of the personality, the  epistemic  understanding of the personality being gestalt, I need to find ways of holistic living, preserving the authenticity of character, giving room to proper positioning in ways that allow easy switching of polar activities without a need to induce zeal through the stimulation of the senses.

Thursday, February 13, 2020

Devotional: PLEASURE CAN BECOME PUNISHMENT

Poem of the Day: Shrove Tuesday by Celia Warren

Entries:

         It’s 1:22 AM, I’m learning, as always, a natural disciplined being bent on conquering the folds of existence.

         A sterile culture lacking novelty at its base is a misconception of acute discerning of the true needs of being. The inability of a people to understand the ever encompass of spatial reality morphing, is the lack of good archetypal characters with viable roles that fulfil the sincere outcry for existential fulfilment. The pulling away from stories that inhibit the subjugation of natural phenomenon at its base level is to fulfil the urging need for acceptance in a world that constantly divides and labels.

         Changing the method of study, based on an end different from previously incepted processes, has led at the arrival of this search, I’ll be picking up a book, in hopes I find methods that impact, in contrast to ephemeral impressions. I’ll be reading  Moonwalking with Einstein , a stray from proposed intentions, a foray to much needed mental juice for this life-long inquisition.

Lesson Bits:

         An excerpt from today’s devotional “it’s important to connect the so-called temptation with its actual effects. Once you understand that indulging might actually be worse than resisting, the urge begins to lose its appeal. In this way, self-control becomes the real pleasure, and indulgence becomes the regret.

Fun Facts:

         Dom DeLuise, celebrity fat man (five of clubs), has been implicated in the following unseemly acts in my mind’s eye: He has hocked a fat globule of spittle (nine of clubs) on Albert Einstein’s thick white mane (three of diamonds) and delivered a devastating karate kick (five of spades) to the groin of Pope Benedict XVI (six of diamonds). Michael Jackson (king of hearts) has engaged in behavior bizarre even for him. He has defecated (two of clubs) on a salmon burger (king of clubs) and captured his flatulence (queen of clubs) in a balloon (six of spades). Rhea Perlman, diminutive Cheers bartendress (queen of spades), has been caught cavorting with the seven-foot-seven Sudanese basketball star Manute Bol (seven of clubs) in a highly explicit (and in this case, anatomically improbable) two-digit act of congress (three of clubs).

Friday, February 14, 2020

Devotional: THINK BEFORE YOU ACT

Poem of the Day: Valentine by Wendy Cope

Entries:

         The day of love, it’s 9:57 AM, I’m elated in my heart; that’s just how I feel. I’ll be penning down two poems today, it’s the day of love, one for Stephanie, another for Esperanza, to love, as we tick away to the inverse bang.

         Understanding my triggers, from audible to visual, it’s important I resist temptations; from the lesson bits of yesterday. I need to understand that I have done nothing wrong by improving on myself, I am doing myself a great service by forging on and implementing the best form of technology that builds my mind, and ensures an utmost throughput. Understanding, that my environment is different from the inside world of tranquil, positioning my attention at the laser motion of important impressions, believing that situations are nothing but what they are; external forces with simple blunt invitations that can’t perturb or seize my attention if I don’t break the bond of personal purpose and veneration. Implementing the safe measure of pushing out any self that hopes to validate already concluded, reviewed substrates of understanding and loci flames of purpose, avoiding alluring applications of mitigation with aim of disturbing my rest.

         Today is a day of love, but right now I feel hate, its 12:55 PM. Hate is an emotion that stirs out of envy, the envy I feel is the fact that you wielded the power to hurt me. In time I will put a cross around you, a symbol of the hate I feel for you, to stir and feel when you find someone you love.  Anonymous neighbor .

         I was hoping to write haiku poems, but I changed my mind, I’ll rather express the pleasures of my heart, how you make me feel; your love, will you still love me if ever I’m not just yours? Will you be mine if I ever seem screwy? Will you understand the love behind my past mistakes? Will you love my  consumed ; my heart? My mistakes? Dear Lulu.

         If pernicious subtle uttered wicked thoughts and acted actions, directed at no one but self; camouflaged from the immediate conscious impression of perception; disguised from the awareness of, intended by inherent intentions of deceiving whom the aimed perceiver is, eventually get to one, know this is a beam at shadows of the loopholes of the mind caught. If living becomes a rationale at understanding objectively what this reality is, with paranoia being an allusion to the impossible nature of a man who seeks to understand the inchoate words of a mob. When this happens, know there has been a distraction of willed attention, leading to paralysis of directional intention, since perception has been seized; focus hijacked. The solution is to ask - what is the ideal idiosyncratic position of purpose at the current time?

         It’s 10:35 PM, and I’m yet to write the poems, I’ll get dinner now and get to it.

To-do:

Implementing the safe measure of pushing out all self that hopes to validate already concluded, reviewed, substrates of understanding and loci flames of purpose.

EDIT (12/03/2020 11:33A.M):

Process of achieving this has begun, with the introduction of the indifferent spectator, I call her BusiSkrit.

Saturday, February 15, 2020

Devotional: ONLY BAD DREAMS

Poem of the Day: All You Need Is Love by John Lennon and Pau

Entries:

         It is 9:51 AM, not a bad weekend, I’ll be giving my all today, reigniting the passion for wisdom, the utter awe at the collective contrast in a world of ideas, I’ll keep my heart, bring the demon beyond the event horizon.

I planned on using the weekend for mnemonic purpose; planned on committing to memory the new words I have ascribed to communicative significance.

         Not getting caught up in swirls of unnecessary brandishing events, like unsolicited side talks and unanimous remarks, remains key to avoiding and abolishing the massive insanity of collective ideologies that seek to systematically retain reason while destroying intellectual forms of harnessing individual potentials.

         Happiness is for animals, as an intellectual being of reason, fleeting is synonymous to emotions. To hold on to happiness is to valley in on a lesser way of being with the objective supposition of happiness being based on morals; the ideological mode of carriage and deportment.

EDIT(30/04/2020):

Happiness depends on one’s disposition. it also requires the exclusion of many other things; it can only exist in a closed space, an allusion to the concept to valley in on a lesser way of being.

EDIT (22/05/2020):

A quote from a book I’m currently reading: the Manifesto of art by Ayn Rand, the topic being THE PSYCHO - EPISTYMOLOGY OF ART:  One type of art tells him that disasters are transient, that grandeur, beauty, strength, self-confidence are his proper, natural state.   The other tells him that happiness is transient and evil, that he is a distorted, impotent, miserable little sinner, pursued by leering gargoyles, crawling in terror on the brink of an eternal hell.  Quotes from ancient Greece, and the middle ages, showing the disparity in metaphysical truths leading to normative abstractions that still seeds a flourishing civilization and the other, the darkest hours of history. The consequences of both experiences are obvious—history being their practical demonstration.

Wednesday, February 26, 2020

Devotional: TO EACH HIS OWN

Poem of the Day: The Poetry Grand National by Roger Stevens

Entries:

         Today is another amazing day, I wake up a bit offset from my conditioned norm, but It’s fine, I wake up, get my thoughts together, strobe my brain to action, and get to the day’s waking motions. It’s a bit of a drill, getting these thoughts down; filling up my journal. Always an urge to get the devotional opened early in the day, but I find myself still sleepy as I said earlier, it’s more of an environment thing than a personal thing, it’s fine though, head is above water, and I’m striding on with my sight on both ends of my peripheral vision clearly perceived.

My dad’s out, I’m filling up his deposit of water, I slide to his sitting room, find his bag a bit out of place, I peer in, find an A4 sheet, turn it over, discovering a list of some sort for an association on commercial motorcycle taxis for a particular geographical area, only to find my name as vice-chairman. Okay that’s a rude way of discovering anything that consequential, I don’t know what to think of it, I’m just a bit aloof about it. Choosing not to give it much thought, I’ll just let it slide. It’s fine.

         An excerpt from today’s reading of city girls by Elizabeth Gilbert:  He preferred the grit and glitter of the theatre world to the polish and repression of café society .

         We used to be interested in inquisitive studying and learning, now all we care for is to indulge in mindless discussions amid gallivanting acts.

Friday, January 29, 2021

Devotional: KEEP IT SIMPLE

Poem of the Day: from Romeo and Juliet by William Shakespeare

Today's Musical: TRIO FROM ACT 3 DER ROSENKAVALIER BY RICHARD STRAUSS (1864–1949)

Entries:

         A sigh of relief. A bit of luck on your side, I prefer karma on my side, I’m back to my journal, it’s a new year, and it couldn’t have had a better ringing; a connotation of  never losing myself.  A month ago, I inscribed in black ASCII characters, the intention of moving forward alone. A month of playing  hop and grab  at the cookie off the dangling line fastened to a cane. I guess I’m not good enough, I will be, there are materials I need to cover. After being swooned head over heels, it’s only creative to in style space this one out, leaving it where it ends substantively, its place in the continuum of my life.

         All I need today, every day is the knowledge of the value of my own existence, its acknowledgeable forebear, the antecedence that has made it possible for me to be here. The prodding of the anonymous plays only the role of  reminder . These reminders of my personal worth will sash me up, being attributive prerogatives in dealing with life normativity.

         An excerpt from my current read, Music, and the Mind by Anthony Storr:  Bird songs resemble human music both in the sound patterns and in the behaviour setting. Songs illustrate the aesthetic mean between chaotic irregularity and monotonous regularity . . . The essential difference from human music is in the brief temporal span of the bird’s repeatable patterns, commonly three seconds or less, with an upper limit of about fifteen seconds. This limitation conforms to the concept of primitive musicality. Every simple musical device, even transposition and simultaneous harmony, occurs in bird music.

Saturday, July 4, 2020

Devotional: PROTECT THE FLAME

Poem of the Day: For You O Democracy Walt Whitman

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Son To Mother

Entries:

         These past few years have been an inoculation so repetitive and severe; I’ve become . . . I remain dissenting.

         I’ve got a crush on Jessica Andreas, ah . . . if she breaks my heart, I’ll be hurt, I hope it doesn’t take as long as it did to ger over Stephanie—if I’m over her—I remember saying to a friend:  hey, just give it six months, I’ll be fine.  It took me a decade. Hush, tell no one. Well, I’m kinda in love, you know, I feel a certain way; that warm throb that engulfs you like a swirling flame. I miss her, even though knowing what’s like to be with her, her brief instances; of her post. If I lose this, I’ll chalk it up in experience, raise my stained boots and munch up my pride.

         I’ve been turned inside out, growing sick in the air, connected to people who dislike me, some who love me, most who revere me, in all I remain inside out, a match with constant strike outs, a bible of tallied meaning.

         An important except from the book The Stoic Challenge, paraphrased:  The Framing Effect - How we mentally characterize a situation has a profound impact on how we respond to it emotionally. The Stoics realized that we have considerable flexibility in how we frame the situations we experience. Their goal wasn’t to banish emotion but to minimize the number of negative emotions. It is tempting, at this point, to describe the Stoics as patient people, and indeed they were, but a caveat is in order. In one sense, a patient person is one who can suffer a setback without complaint. This is not, however, what the Stoics were doing. Their goal was not to remain calm while suffering a setback but rather to experience a setback without thereby suffering.

         When my second younger sibling comes to mind, I should think of freedom of assembly. She has the right to whatever she pleases; the crowd she wills to be part of. Forgive myself for the times spent harbouring thoughts of disparity.

         Another excerpt: One sign of maturity is a realization of the extent to which you, either intentionally or unintentionally, make life difficult for those around you. We are bad men living among bad men; and only one thing can calm us—we must agree to go easy on one another.

Tuesday, July 7, 2020

Devotional: OUR DUTY TO LEARN

Poem of the Day: Checking Out Me History by John Agard

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Me And My Work

Entries:

         Thinking of all that’s happened, and how my will to fight for life has dwindled, today’s devotional reading says to keep the able stride on, not to give in, to learn the right thing; leave with what counts. I hope I can carry on, for my heart is weak and my strength is far spent, and my love is washed away. I have no face to fight for the man who stands next to me for my resolve has been lost. In the event of my death, if its suicide, I hope these words never get to anyone.

         I miss high-school, singing hymns, my girlfriend up there leading the assembly, thoughts of our last smooch, always the night before, and her sweet Christian praises. Had this go through my head while seeing a movie.

         Banshee’s mum is a stupid person, who just like the other Scrompus, the stupid bitch who has life in the mist gone has lost her mind. She bears no consequence on her actions and just like my mum’s kids. Her’s will bear the burden if they don’t wake to the reality of things. No one is ever high enough to fall.

         I discovered the concept of  curse of knowledge  reviewing the last chapter read from the Skepticism course and I’m thinking—as my blood flows, strewing veins that transit stuff of the gods—how biased have I become? Away from my resolve, mindless, by the planes of the outskirts of my inferential know. See, this is a bit tawny—as it were—a mix of the brown and the yellow. Figuring out  what is what?  Am I the brown? Is that what I would have volitionally willed? My propensity? Or am I the yellow, the obvious? Or still, am I somewhere in there, in the discrete, lost in the composition, forever lost in the world of labels, caught away in a colour? To figure these things out, I’ll need to understand this concept—Curse of Knowledge—and how I can better delineate who I am, or at least, what I choose to stand for, what counts for an improvement, and what sits as corruption, knowing there is a normal psychology of belief that allows for outside influences.

         Body on heads, still my skin is dry and ugly. Head over body, still I count a twine at its turns. I’m sick and I can get no help, still I’m my help. Body on heads. I’ll keep safe.

         Thinking of it; all the trouble I go through during the day. The only time I’m ever down or sad at my existence is when I wake up. Waking up in a ditch-bed, a subtle strong reminder of remiss; waking up from mortal  sleep  after I took that cup of shaving powder that should have ended this existence. The after fact of my inability to down it when I should have, quite early, following its preparation, part hunts me every morning. A reinitiation into the turmoils of my life here need not be beard, I’m tired, and a misuse of an opportunity is light of cowardice. These things should be written, reread, understood, so in the relapse to the phase of not being able to endanger the existence that holds bare in a life of wondrous things, I’ll pull off my tie, say I fought a good one, and all things like my life, must come to an end.

         Sometimes hackneyed words are meant. Regardless you should always call people on their bullshit.

         An excerpt from the course on Skepticism:  Once we have an idea in our minds about something, we notice only evidence that confirms the idea and are blind to evidence that disconfirms it.

         The intentions behind this entry are frazzled and worn out, reason, I have spoken on them countless times. My mum is sick and I think it’s born out of a loss of a lot, I can’t begin to list them all, but one idea would be a neglect of what is important.

         Most audiobooks are just filled with cynicism.

         Just thinking of this same audiobook, it has me thinking how in the undulation of history, a lot of books are lost in the tides of history, never to make it to the halls of the classic. I also think the cynicism is a call to attention, to listen to what is being said.

         This is a twist of fate, another input included on 16:41, 24th July 2021. I currently am seeing the  The Long Pond Studio Sessions  and discovering the lyric from the song  seven  that reads:

 Please picture me

 In the trees

 I hit my peak at seven feet

 In the swing

 Over the creek

 I was too scared to jump in

 But I, I was high in the sky

 With Pennsylvania under me

 Are there still beautiful things?

 Trees  like  blue  means conversation to me.

         Line seven holds my favourite, repetitions I have come now to bear a match with  you and I , line  five  first is of interest, it’s a brace of the   withholding of affirmation as I blurted the line:

 Hitch this shit together

 Like lil locked up

 Like creek or leather

 … I might just listen

 … the error

         The most important line to the epiphany in expression is line  four , (also numero uno) great braid pattern: poem  19 :  meeting a girl is like swinging a set.  Weird how since I wrote these poems, numbers now carry some personal meaning. I especially like the time-lines:  02:44 ,  02:47 .

         02:44: reads  clue  on  shitFreestyle,  same number of words in the mentioned poem. 44th day poem is  home , 44th poem in the series is  every  from day 33.

         02:47: reads  together,  the number of words in  half blue pod , interesting. LOL. The 47th day poem is  electric.  The 47th poem in the series is Charly Cox. LOL: Familial.

Friday, July 10, 2020

Devotional: LOVE THE HUMBLE ART

Poem of the Day: The Magic of the Mind by Clive Webster

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Televised

Today's Musical: FELIX MENDELSSOHN [1809 - 1847] - SONGS WITHOUT WORDS ( OPUS 19 NO. 1 IN E MAJOR )

Entries:

         Today marks the first day of my use of the daily reference book: Year of Wonder, and today’s musical is by Jakob Ludwig Felix Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, German musician and romantic composer of orchestral and choral works, who was born today 1809, died 1847.

         The distended bellies of the starving cows, OMG how many cows do I know?

         I wrote a Haiku for Jessica, it goes:

 In the event Jess

 Seat next to seat don’t warm hearts

 Miss only, the corn.

         Just as I was about writing the next one some dude calls saying he’s pastor Olofin, a call for my mum, well I think Olofin is pronounced the way he did as a kind of euphemism. It may mean something else, that I don’t know.

Another haiku for my crush Jessica

 Cock-a-doodle-doo

 You sprout my sombre heart bloom

 With sultry tunes um . . .

Another one:

 Clocks ticking through lines

 Heels missing on the right side

 Heaven waits here now

 If it is, isn’t

 Lead me on beyond ends wait

 Mirth taste in your gait

         I have been fvcking jinxed, I'm in love with a pop star. OMG!

         I want to write another, but I guess I should know when to stop.

So here is another:

 Whistle kiss issues

 Your music my soul crush in

 Like pestle thuds.

Five Haikus now, I couldn’t pen down one on valentine’s day, and here I am, with five in the name of love.

Saturday, July 11, 2020

Devotional: THE START-UP OF YOU

Poem of the Day: The Duel by Eugene Field

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Nothing Much

Today's Musical: ELLA FITZGERALD LOUIS ARMSTRONG BESS, YOU IS MY WOMAN NOW

Entries:

         I’ve been Lazy all day, laying lazy even though today’s devotional talks about the start-up of self. I guess this is mine, I took half a pill earlier this morning to sleep, took the other this morning after breakfast, I guess that’s why I’m this way. It’s 3:05 PM. I guess I’ll be filling my responsibilities. This morning was exciting, so I was on twitter, woke up around 2:03 A.M, and loading up twitter, with three minutes in, Jessica’s account records an activity, and I used the opportunity to post my Haikus. In minutes, she tweets saying something about, being about it. Here is the tweet:  don’t say it if you don’t fucking mean it.

         I was a bit confounded, thought of it a while. Do I post something, saying I tried to taper off the effect of my honest words? But then I’d be insecure all my life if I did that, I didn’t post anything. I took my mind off it, surfed YouTube a while. I later switched tabs, and saw she posted a picture, one of a couple or a date pair at a table having ice-cream from a goblet in a saucer, on closer look-up I realized it’s a shot from a 2001 movie called  Serendipity . I downloaded, but it isn’t complete yet. Well, what I guess is, the former tweet wasn’t for me. I guess she meant it for someone else. I’ll guess she’d rather have us go out on that kinda date than a cinema. My post might be off a bit, it’s because I’m just somewhere, lol.

         I’m adding this entry as a means, a reminder; a way of getting back to this important statement from the composer Felix Mendelssohn on the debate of music and its nature of meaning, it says:  What the music I love expresses to me is not thought too indefinite to put to words but too definite to put to words . This sentiment flies in the face of those who have declared that music is too abstract to have an actual meaning, what the narrator ensues from this is  if a piece moves you in a certain way, brings to mind certain images or stories, it doesn’t matter if what you’re interpreting is what was intended, if it gives you what the incident might call many feels, it means what it means .

         This input is important for reasons that don’t necessary matter to me, but still will be elucidated in full for its pleasure; disambiguation. The name Wiayu and its connote is now a thing for folks, apart from the fact that it’s a song by Skrillex and Diplo feat Justin Bieber off of the Jack U album, the album that says instead of doing drugs, why not do some Jack U - listen to the album - is now used in certain circles as a taboo word. Just this morning I called my friend and he refused to reply me when I asked where he was, pretending not to hear me, this isn’t the first time, it’s been of incidence. My only reason for calling this out, is my stumbling on the concept of Diffeomorphism Invariance, meaning  what’s going on at a point in space depends only on that point, and not where it’s located, nor what’s happening at other points . This might not necessarily tie things together directly, but from a cognition level in lieu of the former, I’d like this post to remain as a reference. Bear in mind that Diffeomorphism Invariance is based on the concept of Loop Quantum Gravity and this, has no confirming data.

         I need to reboot my devotional, I mean living the maxims, whether it calls me out, admonishes or advises me.

         So in a lecture about loop quantum gravity, Dr Don Lincoln is wearing a shirt with Einstein on it with his tongue out and his left eyebrow looking avian like, its plain funny.

Sunday, July 12, 2020

Devotional: SOME SIMPLE RULES

Poem of the Day: Jerusalem (from Milton) by William Blake

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Glory Falls

Today's Musical: NOCTURNO, OP. 7 BY FRANZ STRAUSS (1822–1905)

Entries:

         The preface to today’s poem, I quote it here for its beauty.

          The Stolen and Perverted Writings of Homer & Ovid, of Plato & Cicero, which all men ought to contemn, are set up by artifice against the Sublime of the Bible; but when the New Age is at leisure to Pronounce, all will be set right, & those Grand Works of the more ancient & consciously & professedly Inspired Men will hold their proper rank, & the Daughters of Memory shall become the Daughters of Inspiration. Shakspeare & Milton were both curb’d by the general malady & infection from the silly Greek & Latin slaves of the Sword.

          Rouze up, 0 Young Men of the New Age! set your foreheads against the ignorant Hirelingsl For we have Hirelings in the Camp, the Court & the University, who would, if they could, for ever depress Mental & prolong Corporeal War. Painters! on you I call. Sculptors! Architects! Suffer not the fashonable Fools to depress your powers by the prices they pretend to give for contemptible works, or the expensive advertizing boasts that they make of such works; believe Christ & his Apostles that there is a Class of Men whose whole delight is in Destroying. We do not want either Greek or Roman Models if we are but just & true to our own Imaginations, those Worlds of Eternity in which we shall live for ever in JESUS OUR LORD.

         I’ve been reading the book on Stoicism by the same author of my Daily devotional,  The Stoic Challenge - William B. Irvine . And I found this important point referenced from a book been spoken about, it’s called  On Death and Dying by Elisabeth KüblerRoss  and here it is quoted:  The five stages of grief: denial, anger, bargaining, depression, and finally, acceptance. These were the stages, she said, that those diagnosed with a terminal illness typically go through—and the stages that these individuals should go through to effectively deal with grief.  I’ll be downloading this book, dealing with the voices, I feel like I’ve gone through these stages, in order to get a more nuanced healing; understanding, I’ll be getting this book.

Monday, July 13, 2020

Devotional: A LEADER LEADS

Poem of the Day: The Argument of His Book by Robert Herrick

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

London

Today's Musical: STRING QUARTET IN G MAJOR, OP. 76 NO. 1 1: ALLEGRO CON SPIRITO BY JOSEPH HAYDN (1732–1809)

Entries:

         Back at my time at Wiayu, the ingenuous me, easily trusting, quick to embrace everyone’s motive as of good intention. How do I move forward from here? How do I tread the line between being a cynic and being receptive?

         In today’s musical, I discovered Joseph Haydn, a great composer of the 18th century, I’ll be getting his works, it’s said—there is a piece of string quartet for every mood.

         The habit of brushing “scruffy” nose, a carefree attitude towards immediate urgency, that’s what it is. The need for having a proper way of heuristic learning, memory aiding, mnemonics maybe? I need to figure other methods of remembering. Putting markers on things as store. When I can’t control these agents, it won’t work in remembering, maybe comprehending not remembering.

         My heart is still broken as it were, and this feeling I have for Jessica is going nowhere.

         A quote from the book Messiah quoting Jung:  When we analyse the persona we strip off the mask, and discover that what seemed to be individual is at bottom collective; in other words, that the persona was only a mask of the collective psyche. Fundamentally the persona is nothing real: it is a compromise between individual and society as to what a man should appear to be . . . The persona is a semblance, a two-dimensional reality, to give it a nickname.

         A psychological instrument in the Stoic tool kit is negative visualization. It’s imperative involves making a point of imagining ways in which my life could be worse. It is important to realize that in advising me to negatively visualize, the Stoics aren’t advocating that I dwell on how things could be worse; that would indeed be a recipe for misery. Instead, what I should do is periodically have flickering thoughts about how my life and circumstance could be worse.

Sunday, July 26, 2020

Devotional: WHEN GOOD MEN DO NOTHING

Poem of the Day: Watching My Dog Sleep by Kate Tempest

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

They Ask Why

Today's Musical: DÉPLORATION SUR LA MORT DE JEHAN OCKEGHEM BY JOSQUIN DES PREZ (C. 1450–1521)

Entries:

         Where do I start? It has been all hell. I would be denying the much-awaited awakening I deserve if I refuse to admit the loss from the days spent away from my journal. This rain had a reaction out of a lure, and still as I type this, I must run away to see her pictures, like a fiend.

         Today is a day of reckoning, I am back to my ways—reading—and it is obvious how far I have strayed, as my reading has become slow and my attention has lost its focus, I’m transfixed by this.

         I have deleted her pictures, videos, I’m not happy, I even lost all need for listening to my daily poems. It happened on a morning I set out for the text for the daily poem, I couldn’t find the text in any of the search results so I went for a video, the account read Mr. Butler and that was it, I got engulfed by the laziness it incited. In time I found the enemy, the game-mind saying quietly to go against the grain, when the poem says true, it quietly whispers false, now I must say bye. Now I know, truly I’m all alone, and this is the way it will remain, I certainly feel washed away as I wrote as a comment to a post of Jessica.

         Logic could be right or false, here is the definition of logic.  Logic is the systematic study of the   forms of inference  , the relations that lead to the acceptance of one proposition; the conclusion, on the basis of a set of other propositions; the premises. More broadly, logic is the analysis and appraisal of deductive arguments.   The premises may or may not support the conclusion  ; when they do not,   the relation   is characterized as a fallacy. it deals with inferences whose validity can be traced back to the formal features of the representations that are involved in that inference, be they linguistic, mental, or other representations.

Thursday, June 3, 2020

Devotional: IT IS WELL TO BE FLEXIBLE

Poem of the Day: from Childe Harold’s Pilgrimage by George Gordon, Lord Byron

Entries:

         I’ve been off for a while now, I just need to get it back all together, been working on getting a contract - a deal from a friend. Using proceeds I’ll be getting a new laptop, my younger sibling, the immediate one, has asked to have her laptop back as she needs it for her upcoming exam. I’ll be fine though, I’m done with the introduction, all I need is the deal to slide in.

         Love is divine, following through time its destined attraction, through primary school. Oh I had so many, Kelechi and Jumoke . . . I’m writing all these because I’m trying to dispose the thought of whom my first best friend is, that’s Peter? Riding the backstreet. I had a girl on the first day of high-school. Memories in my mind.

         These girls might be the same, but our hearts aren’t the same.

         Clocking 34, clocking 52, new ones. New ones.

         This idea of arriving at a point of being so independent—nothing restricts—in the allure of not wanting to be dehumanized is a loss of what it means to be human, the arrival at the Homo sapien.

         Dagny is so intelligent.

         I’ll let the sun eclipse me.  Wide eyes will always brighten the blue .  You can’t whisper above the thunder but you can fly anywhere.   Purple burst of paper birds, this   picture paints a thousand words, so take a breath of myth and mystery and don’t look back.  Owl City, Adam Young has written some of the best words to hit my eardrums, and no one like Taylor Swift to help me feel grounded even if stoned hocussed. Lol. Both medallions.

Friday, June 12, 2020

Devotional: A TRAINED MIND IS BETTER THAN ANY SCRIPT

Poem of the Day: On Turning Ten by Billy Collins

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Is Love

Entries:

         I discovered today, that, out of the abusive manipulation and bombardment from the collective—the game-mind—a creeping wave of chorea has set in. I don’t know how certain my prognosis is, but my body’s reaction; my face threw jerky movements to the right of my upper jaw, just below my cheeks. I was trying to switch my attention; my attempt was a very brusque one. This reminds me of the day my dad came around when I was having breakfast, and he got upset over the fact that I had an egg with my meal, further dismissing, of the unimportance of my Left Ventricular Hypertrophy, my pains, and imposing further his will, taking away his pillowcase. I tried to make light of the mood, a flinch from what? . . . resulting in anxiety.

         I discovered the artist of the monicker  Role Model  has a similar timbre to that of  Jesse  from  The Neighborhood .

         An objective way of greeting departure: Goodbye and good premises.

         “People develop a global knowledge structure which contains cohesive, whole knowledge  internalized from experience”:  The need for experience, an aid in learning opposing to  Domain-specific learning  theories. The excerpt is from a Wikipedia article on Domain-general learning.

         Anne Frank was born today. Her memories and her humanity will forever remain with me.

Sunday, June 14, 2020

Entries:

         Understanding how knowledge of computation enhances how one sets out in understanding language, says a lot about “Bleeding heart” and my current traverse. Doing some more programming work should help my writing, I’ll need to get a laptop first, next I’ll be working on what? Can’t tell . . . maybe. It’s fine.

         I need to understand that as I change, the world doesn’t change with me, only I change, I need not check behind my back, it’s all me, I’m the one doing the change, it’s my resolve, my shift, my progress, the chatter and noise is an everlasting background noise that will slowly recede to the unobserved as I ever get busy at what is of importance to me. No one is of importance in that chatter, not even a call of my name, not a voice of my past self, not an echo of my thought, all that matters is me, my change, my progress and my goals.

         It’s good to start early, the brain might be neuroplastic, but it is the same nerves that get in the way. I must thank my brain for edging me on quite early, reading books that switched my premises; an evolution in the life of a wanderer. Maybe this is just an instance of the Dunning-Kruger effect in action?

         I got to know that Lions are of beige colour.

         Hearing the voice of my ex outside when it’s probably just a recording has me pissed, rousing soppy thoughts, but instead I’ll pick my demeanour up and remain stolid, my countenance stern.

Monday, June 22, 2020

Devotional: THE DEFINITION OF INSANITY

Poem of the Day: Recessional by Rudyard Kipling

Entries:

         So I had this can of malt given to me by my parents, only to smell it after couple of sips; to perceive its repugnant odour of cockroach.

         Understanding the difference between insanity and a pretence of value provoked out of deep-seated empirical based meaning is to delve into the abject misery of insanity. My informed narrative is born of apprehension—resolved in a feat. A trickle of constant misinformation holds no water at my basal contingent. The future stands in objective discernment for those with the right mantle. Words elude those without understanding, a loss of the fact that  truth is truth , never wavering.  For the physical science is a substrate on which the humanities should stand , any view away from this is a fallacy, a cognitive bias, a deep-running crippling daemon process; a final hindsight bias.

         Language is ever evolving, changing to meet the growing needs of an ever developing world. The Yoruba language in its colloquial use, remains one of a myriad of impossible feats; a range of symbols forcing itself on an ever growing expanding meaning set. Grouping in bands, a growing nuanced substrate. The result is a blindness so great. Even a borrowing of a foreign language can’t fix. In my inmate state of mind; current conditioning, I say and state clearly out of remiss: I will never ever keep to heart the words of a tribe that chases insanity in an ever twisting monotony of already based meaning, the overuse of trite words in describing largely disparate domains. To not change or grow in that regard is to chase flies on a sore hollowed.

         Forgive my reticence as my present conditioning is its predispose.

         Be careful in your studying, on continuing—especially when distracted—lest you build upon sands, instead of rocks. When your mind says no, let your brain seize as its own, the proclivity, dismiss all whims—straddling through what once was, and what matters. What permits continuity in the path of understanding is the honest endeavour, even if it means, reading some paragraphs again.

         Well, I realized today, people can perceive the thoughts of the mind. I wonder what I’ll be doing with that, knowing is conceding.

         I think I am Nightswan now, I was Theonator, then I was Theophil.  I am born anew now . A commentary from a text I wrote some time ago.

 My music, musings . . . the flower, the net profit of my existence . . . the living being

 Theo from Theos, meaning God

 Phil, an affinity for a thing, origin from the word Phile, meaning loving.

 TheoPhil means an affinity for the creator, the supreme being, the love. God loving.

 I got this idea on my first use of empathogens, weed to be precise, I had this feeling of being so loved, I felt all songs were renditions portraying the inherent love bursting in the emotions of the singers or artist; an allusion, the personalisation of the love.

 Subliminally came this name on a day of writing, I was TheoNator before my first weed use.

 I got the name Theonator from Terminator, more like God detonator or destroyer, I grew up mad at God, like a phobia, not liking him; having not answered my prayers. Couldn't deduce why my lost textbooks wouldn't materialize in my room.

 A journey of Theonator to TheoPhil. Here I am, TheoPhiL the often inordinate . . . rapture singer.

 Enjoy the bootleg - soon copyrighted - romanticism inspired work of my growing, to be colossal anthology.

         So I had looked up the word “enough” today, my mind is in shit, I can’t deny it. I miss words when I write.

Sunday, June 28, 2020

Devotional: NO SELF-FLAGELLATION NEEDED

Poem of the Day: A Bird Came Down the Walk by Emily Dickinson

Entries:

         Today starts rainy, I wake up really early, it’s still raining, I guess it’ll drizzle all day, it’s currently 10:50 A.M, I’m lying on my bed and the thought of all I’ll read is precedent above all things. Read a chapter off the skepticism course, I’ll be reading another.

Earlier today I sent a text message to my dad pleading he help me with my visa appointment process, the need to not be dependent upon his handouts has been made known by me; this was at a meeting yesterday.

         I noticed in different instances of seeing videos, especially when playback speed is adjusted to 1.50x, that the motion feels entirely natural, but on reversing back to the default speed 1.00x, there is a sense of it being slow, an almost lull effect, I think this is as a result of habitual premise. This is closely related to addiction—drug use—and how it changes perception of normalcy.

         I started with the physics course and the first video I enjoyed was  the origins of mass  and it detailed the different effects of atomic particles in mass sum ratio. The particle with the heaviest contribution seems to be a hadron called the meson, even though it wasn’t implicitly stated. What was introduced was the idea of the binding force holding the nucleon particles, I only discovered the meson through a vague look-up of keywords. I’ll continue with the videos today.

         I’m waiting for breakfast and I feel like Igor Stravinsky maybe I should have my head on the floor for a blood rush. It’s not like I’m having a block, I’m just hungry.

-- edit | Monday, June 29, 2020 --

         I discovered this definition in the dictionary. A Pi-meson is a meson involved in holding the nucleus together; produced as the result of high-energy particle collision. This appears closer, amounting for much of the mass. I also discovered all other sorts of meson.

Tuesday, June 30, 2020

Devotional: THE OBSTACLE IS THE WAY

Poem of the Day: Ulysses by Alfred, Lord Tennyson

Entries:

         It’s evening already, 4:40 P.M, I’m listening to Astrid S  Dance , typing away, well . . . what else . . . I listened to a complete song from a bird just out my window. I guess it’s drawing closer to that time of the year—my place. The reason for this entry is finally, I got a crack on the theory of relativity, the spacetime paradigm shift from space and time—space and time being different dimensions—and the keynote of my discovery is the concept of time. When speed increases time reduces, well that’s simple intuition, time here isn’t  time , like the Gregorian, it’s relative time. As you move faster, your clock slows down—in relation. This clearly expresses the phenomenon of time dilation. The central idea being, every object moves through spacetime at one speed: The speed of light. Another important point to note about the theory of relativity is its percept of every point being the centre of the universe, calculations are computed with no external reference point. At the heart of relativity is a change of point of view.

         Einstein's theory of relativity is live and let live.

Saturday, March 7, 2020

Devotional: DON’T TRUST THE SENSES

Poem of the Day: To My Sister by William Wordsworth

Entries:

         Woke up this morning feeling great, meditated, got to listening in on some cool tracks and now I’m about to bathe. It’s good to be alive, I hope I get to do a lot today.

         After writing my dad a letter, hoping in disguise I’m writing a letter to myself; in hopes that I get an empathic reply, I figured on re-reading, I discover I have an acquiesce to look forward to: a response from my dad stating if his volition has been of good intent.

Below is a true copy of the letter.

          Whatever game you’re playing whether through direct contact or through means elusive, kindly note my understanding is diminishing and my resort is to keep all I brace important away from you.

          If you find this offensive, please know I’m offended and the only recourse is to leave me to my own devices.

          I’m no child, neither am I clinically sick, if my judgements are wrong based on “facts” you raised me by; building on from, are lies, then know I ‘ll remain disappointed even after you read this.

          I can no longer fold my arms while you pretend not to be aware of who I am.

          This will be the only form of accusal at a narrative I’ve come to perceive in your ways.

          You know my mistakes, all of them. I may not know yours but I can feel their scornful effects.

         In Émile, or on education by Jean-Jacques Rousseau he talks about the way in which a human being left to his devices will naturally be good, hence the notion  the noble savage .

Tuesday, March 10, 2020

Devotional: FIND YOURSELF A CATO

Poem of the Day: Remember by Christina Rossetti

Entries:

         Today’s reading from the stoic devotional admonishes the utmost reason why an entity of ethical distinction is important in the life of every individual, going on to suggest how this entity needs not be a real or physical individual, but could be a conceptualized being of rationality. Adam Smith comes up with a term for this, it’s called the  indifferent spectator.

         In the build up to the novel I’m coming up with,  Aragascar: the devil’s eye . And the new book I’m reading to help me with it,  Story Genius,  I will be going ahead to start early and will develop a character that will stand intermittently as my impartial spectator. I’ll call her  Busiskrit.

         I’ll let you in on all the juicy details as I come up with patterns, principles, suppositions, anecdotes, and axioms, she embodies.

         I learned today, who the 26th president of the United States is. He’s Theodore Roosevelt. I smell like me without a shower in the morning, I should get some on me, but my dad is still home and I need to steal his soap. Arrgh… my life is a waste of potential, but I’m on my way to the eye of the storm.

Wednesday, March 11, 2020

Devotional: LIVING WITHOUT RESTRICTION

Poem of the Day: Mothering Sunday by George Hare Leonard

Entries:

         Recording this as a reminder of the fact that I learned it once, the city of Munich which is the capital of Bavaria, a southwestern state in Germany, known for beer and factories that create automobiles is also the state Einstein moved with his parents. He would have actually been persecuted if he was in the German state during the holocaust, I guess the one’s with the brains always know when to leave the state. Like I’ll be leaving Nigeria.

If elder Ayeni is seen by the plastic bender (supposed Engineer) as a poor seated believer then the man who raises kids to be dispersed as failed investments is what?

         Father doesn’t acknowledge son’s work . . . why? He never intended to have him supersede him.

         An excerpt from today’s reading of the law of one “with the same range of human emotions”.

         To have wishes, is to set conditions for desire . . .

         I’m going down the lanes of memory. it’s an introspective analysis on how the only friend I had with me with the close tag, never cared about aesthetics,  Jinx , he went to Paris, took a picture at the Eiffel tower, with his face shut off; his hands covering his face, I think it says a lot. The reason I say this is, he could have taken the picture at night with the lights on, from a distance, I think that would have been better. I know this is some rant, but better down than ephemeral.

         I learned the end result of habituating in an environment like mine is to end up with the “Tourette’s syndrome“.

Lesson Bits:

         To have wishes, is to set conditions for desire, karma-yoga says the “not getting attached to the fruits” ensures utmost efficiency.

         Human identity is itself a narrative construction – that who we are is, in a very real sense, a product of who we tell ourselves we are; when neurological disease complicates this picture (by, for example, telling us that our wife is a hat), we are able to glimpse this story-of-ourselves in the process of either being chillingly redacted, or rewritten in order to fictionally compensate for such inconvenient truths about the external world.

Thursday, March 12, 2020

Devotional: Human Affection by Stevie Smith

Entries:

         A quick reminder, the ultimate mode of being in a world with a disposition for action is to be a creator.

         On the collectivism that draws on the thorn of the will through thought manipulation for its bolster. (Still coming to terms with this) In a zero-sum game between the collective and the individual, allotting precisely in all truth, attributes, is primal at analyzing the empirically arrived schemes and methods that lead to proper discerning, presenting the right mode of being that guarantees a probable win.

         I’ll be analyzing all this, informing myself in the process what dots are incognizant, one’s that need be drawn and also the importance of introducing a state of semi-willfulness in the understanding of self: the retracting of the curtain of the parts of the mind that remain fragile and unformed. This leads to an understanding of the individual’s mind, understanding how it responds to impressions of power-shift, from within to without.

         I get it, you don’t want me cos I’ve got a leverage and I’m moving forward.

         Understanding the fact that some angels understand what I want based on traits of personality and probable wants, giving cues on what the next probable plan could be. And also the fact that unseemly demon’s moves in the hopes of suggesting cunning suppositions of foresight when in reality, initial intentions were different.

         Be careful of how you let others control your actions, having your experience substituted from authentic to that which amuses the observer. I will elucidate on this soon.

         How do you handle impromptu prompts, suggestions that lead to a disinterest in running tasks? The key is to recognize that remarks aren’t a connotation of any part of the timeline of a task but rather, stints with aim of power seizure.

Friday, March 13, 2020

Devotional: ONE DAY IT WILL ALL MAKE SENSE

Poem of the Day: Here Comes the Sun by George Harrison

Entries:

         There wills a need for a space for deep work.

         The positioning of self in a state that is independent of any intellectual leverage whether it be a cue or affirmation is necessary in remaining solid. All promulgate should be self-willing. An instance is the belittling of your intellectual strengths; pushing forth, coming to a point of epiphany, only to be sneaked in on by a 3rd party — suggested to in claims of motivation. All that is needed is within. The only factor is the right environment not an impromptu delusion of false hope to be relied on in wait for eventual ridicule; the initial aim of the disposer of innate strengths.

         Reading a book on skepticism and I’m in awe of how much of a half-baked skeptic I am, I’ll be upping my skepticism. Being a good skeptic is the only way to reduce these missteps and minimize harm from them. Here is an excerpt from the book THINK by Cal Newport.

          “Thanks to science, we now understand more than enough about how the human brain works to know that we have to be very careful when trying to determine what is real and what is not, what is true and what is false. If you are human, you can and will be fooled by your own brain in various ways many times throughout your life.   Being a good skeptic   is the only way to reduce these missteps and minimize harm from them.”

=

Thursday, March 19, 2020

Devotional: TIMELESS WISDOM

Poem of the Day: Historical Associations by Robert Louis Stevenson

Entries:

         Today is a beautiful day, I’ve been writing songs, a lot of them, I spent yesterday writing a lot of songs, spent a good time meditating, days before I was caught up in binging; saw the complete season of  Kidding , and it wasn’t bad, I enjoyed every bit of it, I’ll be committing time to completing the book in the series, The Patternist Series:  Patternmaster.  I also have developed keen interest in books like, Sam Harris’s Waking up and also Nathaniel Branden’s The six pillars of self-esteem. I’ll be updating my progress, I honestly hope to finish The Patternist Series this week to begin the Xenogenesis, I saw a review on YouTube and it was a good one, it’s synopsis wasn’t bad.

         An excerpt from today’s reading of the book, Patternmaster:  “I . . . yes, Lord.” As long as he was still alive, he had a chance. Or did he think that only because he wanted so badly to live? No, there was a chance. One could escape physical slavery. The physical leash was not as far-reaching or as permanent as the mental leash.  This is based on the plot of the scene. Two brothers, maternal and paternal inclines, grapple for control; the successor to the pattern, Coransee and Teray. Coransee heads the house, Teray his brother who wills as much power, with a disadvantage, as he leaves school freshly with no house of his own, sold to Coransee by Joachim. He’s got no option left after a battle, to have his lord Coransee place a mental leach on him for the state of an apprentice or remain an outsider, his only option outside of his wish for death.

         Thinking of the community I currently reside in, and the narrative of the “game-mind”, a phrase I’ve come to know after months of moving in. My current analysis is, the aim of this device is, the pernicious diminution of well-being through cognitive hampering; an inhibition at organizing self in states that offer pragmatic ways of living that are utilitarian in form.

         My attentive analytical considerations have included observing at different times how I respond to the constant fissure of directed focus in consciousness, and also the necessity for constant intimidation; a persistent flood of words, remarks that draw for introspective contradiction of already conceptualized standing of organization, peeling at the importance of rational reasoning, the replacement of self-willed action for the passive ways of determinism. The ongoing intimidation was concocted after the keen observation of the subject in natural states of affair, learning the routinised way of affairs, deciding what elates and irritates, on concluding by coming to an awareness of these simple things, an epithet was introduced:  the game mind , dangled as a new way of living, I choose not to elucidate this as I have in the past, the only addition is my new conceptualized understanding of this epithet, an analogy; compared to a game bird, an animal hunted for sport. Since points are counted on successive assaults that lead to derailment of any sort. My understanding of this compound word “game-mind” is the successive belittling of the mind. The frizzling of any keen sense of perception.

(March 23, 2020 appendage)

         On this topic, I choose to write this here, for the reason of keeping all my thoughts on this topic together. In a lecture I just listened to, still yet to digest fully and articulate in an eloquent manner what I mean.

         I will continue to gain momentum, putting action to work by imbibing truth that speaks to me in place of any suggestions - when the enemy tries to switch tactics by claiming to be on my side, dishing out words prior to adjacent intuitive suggestions that the mind arbitrary suggest to self - on taking on such advice.

Lesson Bits:

         course addressing psychedelics, it explicitly says, quoting          Positing the existence of mind at large is more tempting in some states of consciousness than in others but these drugs can also produce mental states that are best viewed as forms of psychosis, as a general manner, I believe that we should be very slow to draw conclusions about the nature of the cosmos on the basis of internal experiences, no matter how profound they may seem.

         From a lecture on scepticism today:  Being a sceptic means be rational and empirical, thinking and seeing before believing and being prepared to be deceived and self-deceived. Scepticism is not seek and ye shall find, but seek and keep an open mind. But what does it mean to keep an open-mind? It is to find the essential balance between orthodoxy and heresy, between a total commitment to the status quo and the blind pursuit of new ideas. Between being open minded enough to accept radical new ideas and not so open minded that your brains fall out. Scepticism is about finding that balance.

Friday, March 20, 2020

Devotional: READY AND AT HOME

Poem of the Day: A Morning Song by Eleanor Farjeon

Entries:

         Today, officially the first day of spring, last of the weekdays, I’ll be finishing  Patternmaster  today, I hope I do though, it’s almost a thing new, to have my words inputted here daily, in time I will be ready for the Busiskrit and my first draft, I mean yes! My story. Well I still love the real world; I just am stuck in a cesspool of ludicrous people with no sense of hope at a life of reasonable good living.

         It’s 8:49 A.M, I just finished the series, awesome. I’ll be reading  Numero zero  by  Umberto Uco , I already started, hopefully I’ll finish it today.

Lesson Bits:

         Excerpts from Sam Harris’s waking up call “The Mystery of Being”.

         Of all the periods in human history that I may have appeared, I live in this one, arguably the first epoch since time-immemorial, now I understand self and circumstance in a truly universal sense, for the first time in history a person’s view of the world need not be dictated by the mere location of birth or religion of parents, now the barrier of geography and language are shattered, down to the ground.

         The philosopher Buttrell Russell  (not sure of name)  described her most rudimentary knowledge of the world as: The knowledge by acquaintance. I.e. - The color of a table standing before you. A quote

           “The particular shade of color that I’m seeing may have many things said about it, I might say that it is brown, rather dark and so on, but such statements though they make me know truths about the color, do not make me know the color itself any better than I did before. So far as concerned the knowledge of the color itself,   as opposed to knowledge of truths about it  . I know the color perfectly and completely when I see it, and no further knowledge of it is even theoretically possible. Thus the sense data which make up the appearance of my table are things with which I have acquaintance, and things immediately known to me, just as they are.”  What Russell seems to overlook here is that this basic knowledge to which no knowledge can be theoretically added is a place where we uncover an intrinsic limit to understanding. Consider any facet of experience, in this case a vision of color; stirring the tide of thoughts long enough to merely observe it as it is, the fact of being in total ignorance of what it is can become obvious.

         What is the color blue? Not as a function of wavelengths of light or neurophysiology, but at it is directly perceived. We’re really left with nothing to say but that it’s blue, which does nothing to clarify things, in fact it’s not even blue, which is just a word; it’s a noise we’re making. What we see before us is whatever it ineffably is. Focusing on this distance between concepts and experience is a means of sneaking up on a truth that is generally described in Buddhism, as the  The truth of emptiness : the idea that no thing has intrinsic independent existence in the way that it seems. The moment we suspend the conceptual associations we have with a given object, or perception; our knowledge about it, our direct experience of it can gray into this experience of pure mystery. We’re left with this wordless intuition of consciousness and its content.

         Meditation isn’t about understanding things conceptually, it’s the ability to experience things more clearly, prior to concepts, it’s the knowledge by acquaintance taking to the highest degree, leading to another state of being: a new form of intelligence, a psychological freedom that a continuous entanglement with concept doesn’t.

         A famous parable from the Buddha meant to get at this difference - A man is struck in the chest by a poison arrow, and a surgeon rushes to his side to begin the work of saving his life, bu the man resist, he wants to know the name of the fletcher who fashioned the arrows shaft, and the type of wood from which it was cut, and the mode of the man who shot it, and the name of the horse upon which he rode, and a thousand other things that have no bearing at all upon his present suffering or his ultimate survival, so this man needs to get his priority straight, his commitment to thinking about  world  results from a basic misunderstanding of his predicament. We too have more problems that will not be solved by more thinking.

Wednesday, March 25, 2020

Devotional: WEALTH AND FREEDOM ARE FREE

Poem of the Day: Today by Billy Collins

Entries:

         I wrote this yesterday, on my phone, planned on including it as an input for yesterday, but it made it for today's.  Treat people who speak stupid, just the way they are - stupid. It makes no sense to pacify yourself in erroneous possibilities of how intelligent they might be. Intuition won’t fix the job of empirical discerning, brace the staff of self, and condemn them to the pits of acquainted fools.

         I have a list of books pending on my  current reading  list, waiting for completion:

The Xenogenesis trilogy,

City of girls,

The lucky one,

Numero zero,

When Nietzsche wept,

The institution, and

Digital fortress.

         Seven books in all, the plan is to not begin any book until I finish these set of books. I plan on also including in my daily readings - a poem each from the book “Poems to live by”, and also a short write-up from the author: Robert Lois Stevenson. Plans to include the precise story and poem will be introduced.

         A beautiful excerpt from today’s reading of The Dawn  “You’re filled with so much life and death and potential for change,” Nikanj continued. “I understand now why some people took so long to get over their fear of your kind.”  Beautiful commentary on the nature of the being of the sapiens.

         Another excerpt from the same book, a remark alluding to the discrepancy of the Yoruba culture from my own views:  “I started out wanting to do exactly that,” Lilith said. “Snoop. Seek. It seemed to me that my culture—ours—was running headlong over a cliff. And, of course, as it turned out, it was. I thought there must be saner ways of life.”

Friday, March 27, 2020

Devotional: PAY WHAT THINGS ARE WORTH

Poem of the Day: Ballad of the Bread Man by Charles Causley

Robert Louis reading of the day:

Something in it

Faith, half faith and no faith at all

The touchstone

The poor thing

The song of the morrow

Entries:

         Woke up feeling indifferent, I choose not to base my mood on my environment, meditating has given me the opportunity to enjoy, even if only briefly, the bask in a vacuum like space, this always has been, but meditating has helped to heighten this tranquil. Also I live most of my time conscious of my present actions, not acting routinely.

         “Gone are the green islands and the bright sea, the sun and the moon and the forty million stars, and life and love and hope. Henceforth is no more, only to sit in the night and silence, and see your friends devoured; for life is a deceit, and the bandage is taken from your eyes.”

         A saying I can’t quote comes to mind, here is a paraphrase “The more you learn, the more of the realization of how little you know”. An allusion to this is the introspective matter of thought while reading the fable,  FAITH, HALF FAITH AND NO FAITH AT ALL.  While on a pilgrimage, a priest, a virtuous man, and an old rover with his axe come across a fakeer on their consecutive stops of deliberative inquisitions into the nature of the priest’s guiding light - his religion. He is later unmoored after successive fallibility. Drawing from my own memories, while on the mandatory internship program in my third year in the university, at computer village, Ikeja. Caught up on a rainy day, outside the office, seeking refuge at a gas station with a colleague, waiting for the rain to subside, a scrawny, untidy man in dirty white coloured robes, a bible under his arm, hobbles past us where we sat knee close to chest, in a traipse manner, he seemed to be begging for alms; more like a mendicant. Befuddled, I asked my older colleague why it was so, he replied succinctly, in words I can’t remember, what he meant goes so:  In life it’s essential to understand all facets of reality.

         The limn of this write-up is the understanding of how impressions can change with new found knowledge.

         An excerpt from today’s reading of the fable  THE TOUCHSTONE  “But he was like the hunter that has seen a stag upon a mountain, so that the night may fall, and the fire be kindled, and the lights shine in his house; but desire of that stag is single in his bosom.”

         Fools can’t recite my knowledge, for that reason, let them tend their business, for theirs is the way of the unhatched smitten egg, devoid of potential.

         As fathers are the a priori base, the foundation of all knowledge in the community, so will my books, knowledge from the old, and insights from today be my guiding light, as they’ve always been.

Night Visions:

Saturday, March 28, 2020

Devotional: COWARDICE AS A DESIGN PROBLEM

Poem of the Day: I Watched a Blackbird by Thomas Hardy

Robert Louis reading of the day:

The man and his friend

The four reformers

The house of eld

Octavia E. Butler’s readings:

The evening and the morning and the night

Near of kin

Crossover

Positive obsession

Furor scribendi

Entries:

          Shipwreck in a sea of faces, there’s a dreamy world, way up there , lines from a song by Adam Young. I figured, sometimes it’s impossible for anyone to reduce the experience of certain activities below a threshold, why? Because old experience wane hard.

         An excerpt from today’s reading of a short story by Octavia Butler: Speech Sounds: “ His use of the left hand interested Rye more than his obvious question. Left-handed people tended to be less impaired, more reasonable and comprehending, less driven by frustration, confusion, and anger. ” Now I don’t know how true this is, but it’s an interesting statement.

         Another excerpt from Octavia Butler’s short story collection titled The Evening and the Morning and the Night.  “The weird part was, I worked hard, got top grades. If you work   hard   enough at something that   doesn’t matter  , you can   forget   for a while about the things that do.”  Now drawing from the incident I was just involved in. Helping my mom with her tea, filling up her flask, random activities of little to no significance, my dad calls me, informing me I’ll need to have the waste made available for the trash collector on his arrival. Dropping the flask in my mom’s room, I move forward to helping with the trash, but first, do I have soap to wash after this dirty activity? No! Is it really important, taking the trash out, when he can just come in to get it? Well, his wife says she doesn’t want the trash collector in the compound, another dictum from the madam, at whose peril actually? His? Mine? Why? I’m not so sure. Just another impudence at the individuals in the household who actually do the work. Mind made up. I don’t plan on taking any trash out, if he needs the trash out, he either plays on whomsoever’s logic is needed to have the trash collector come in, or let his  slave-boy  - me - as I’ve always been, handle it. But no, he won’t. On returning back to the building, after waiting several minutes, intending to ascertain if he, the trash man still is on his way, I meet with Father, telling me I have to take it out, the following conversation ensued, I paraphrase.

Son: Where is the man?

Father: His cart is full. He has gone to empty it; he says he’ll be coming back soon.

Father: Have you taken the trash out?

Son: No, I didn’t.

Father: Why?

Son: I’d rather have him come in to get it.

Father: He can’t come in.

Son: I have no soap to wash after.

         Father gives a scornful remark, imposing his will on mine, I leave his presence, informing him of my defiance as a result of his disdain of my wants. I remember growing up, my dad telling my mom, how he doesn’t know me, he doesn’t know who I am? Think of it. If he doesn’t know who I was, how can he know me; who I currently am? A reference to the letter sent to him should be inferred for proper a priori discerning.

         The reason I relate all these is to draw and infer, showing how easy it is to lose all sense of self, if I had listened to his advice - father - of not reading. I’d be an animal wielded by the raucous of nonchalant individuals with imposing bigoted views, losing sense of the loci flame that has stirred me so far, instead of chasing the wind.

         I switched programs, for the windows media player, with intentions to listen to  Wolf Bite  only to have  The Real World  by  Owl City  played, I was swept away, mood changed, and now I feel lighter; my capricious ass. During the playback, a thought swept through my mind, it was in concession with some lines from the song, how he’d rather live in an imaginary world than live in the real world. I indulge in this by reading books myself, fiction, or non-fiction, any goes, as long as it offers a true episode of escapism, the perfect reverie.

         Reading the fable,  the house of ELD.  I’m taken to the aisle of memory; in view: on the counter. My high-school graduation year book parting words. I paraphrase: “The lord has given us a course to chart during this lifetime, but not without the opportunity to plot ours”. As few as these words are, they signalled the imminent actions, shaped by fore-thoughts, that’d determine the story of my life. So insinuating were the words to my uncle; the proprietor, he avoided speaking to me directly about it, instead meets with my dad admonishing him. For He’d have my dad call me informing me on how, out of condescending spite, I sound intelligent, when all he actually meant was, good lifting.

         A quick summary of the book, he kills the sorcerer, has his right fetter broken, prior to this he . . .

         First it’s a metaphor of how to gain freedom, you need to break down the walls of those you love, fight, conquer . . .

         It so happens that I graduated from high school at fifteen also . . .

Sunday, March 29, 2020

Devotional: WHY DO YOU NEED TO IMPRESS THESE PEOPLE AGAIN?

Poem of the Day: Loveliest of Trees, the Cherry Now by A. E. Housman

Robert Louis reading of the day:

The yellow paint

The penitent

The devil and the innkeeper

Octavia E. Butler’s readings:

Bloodchild

Speech sounds

Entries:

         Avoid people’s claims of redemption, when in truth, the aim is to waste the present, the utility of the moment.

         I discovered my neighbours aren’t the devil, they aren’t humans, they’ve become monotonous impasse of dispute.

         In the last paragraph of the sixth chapter of the LO part, I can clearly infer that the euphoric experience described between the Oankali and the humans isn’t as ecstatic as what I had earlier visualized, for if he (Tino) was truly and deeply pacified and wholly satisfied, the longing for physical contact would be inexistent.

         An excerpt from today’s reading of essays from Butler “ I took archery in high school because it wasn’t a team sport. I liked some of the team sports, but in archery you did well or badly according to your own efforts. No one else to blame. I wanted to see what I could do. I learned to aim high. Aim above the target. Aim just there! Relax. Let go. If you aimed right, you hit the bull’s-eye. I saw positive obsession as a way of aiming yourself, your life, at your chosen target. Decide what you want. Aim high. Go for it. ”

Monday, March 30, 2020

Devotional: REASON IN ALL THINGS

Poem of the Day: The Cherry-Tree Carol by Anon.

Entries:

         An excerpt from a reading of the new intellectual “ Man’s consciousness shares with animals the first two stages of its development:   sensations   and   perceptions  ; but it is the third state,   conceptions  , that makes him man. Sensations are integrated into perceptions automatically, by the brain of a man or of an animal. But to integrate perceptions into conceptions by a process of   abstraction  , is a feat that man alone has the power to perform—and he has to perform it by   choice  . The process of abstraction, and of concept-formation is a process of   reason  , of thought; it is not automatic nor instinctive nor involuntary nor infallible. Man has to initiate it, to sustain it and to bear responsibility for its results. The pre-conceptual level of consciousness is nonvolitional; volition begins with the first   syllogism  . Man has the choice to think or to evade—to maintain a state of full awareness or to drift from moment to moment, in a semi-conscious daze, at the mercy of whatever associational whims the unfocused mechanism of his consciousness produces.

          But the living organisms that possess the faculty of consciousness need to exercise it in order to survive. An animal’s consciousness functions automatically; an animal perceives what it is able to perceive and survives accordingly, no further than the perceptual level permits and no better. Man cannot survive on the perceptual level of his consciousness; his senses do not provide him with an automatic guidance, they   do not   give him the knowledge he needs,   only the material of knowledge  , which his mind has to integrate. Man is the   only   living species who has to perceive reality—which means: to be conscious—by choice. But he shares with other species the penalty of unconsciousness: destruction. For an animal, the question of survival is primarily physical; for man, primarily   epistemological  .

          Man’s unique reward, however, is that while animals survive by adjusting themselves to their background, man survives by   adjusting his background to himself  . If a drought strikes them, animals perish—man builds irrigation canals; if a flood strikes them, animals perish—man builds dams; if a carnivorous pack attacks them animals perish—man writes the Constitution of the United States. But one   does not   obtain food, safety or freedom—by instinct..”

          “Those who could become the New Intellectuals are America’s hidden assets; their number is probably greater than anyone can estimate; they exist in every profession, even among the present intellectuals. But they are scattered in silent helplessness throughout the country, or hidden in that underground which, in human history, has too often swallowed the best of men’s potential:   subjectivity  . They are the men who have long since lost respect for the cultural standards to which they conform, but who hide their own convictions or repress their ideas or suppress their minds, each feeling that he has no chance against the others, each serving as both victim and destroyer. The New Intellectuals will be those men who will come out into the open and have the courage to break that vicious circle.

          If they glance at the state of our culture, they will see that the entire miserable show is kept up by nothing but   routine   and   pretence  , which disguise bewilderment and fear: nobody dares to take the first new step, everybody waits for his neighbour’s initiative. If a society reaches the stage where every man accepts the feeling that he is “a stranger and afraid in a world [he] never made,” the world it gives up will be made by Attila. The greatest need today is for men who are   not strangers to reality  , because they are not afraid of thought. The New Intellectuals will be those who will take the initiative and the responsibility: they will check their own philosophical premises, identify their convictions, integrate their ideas into coherence and consistency, then offer to the country a view of existence to which the wise and honest can repair.

          The New Intellectual will be the man who lives up to the exact meaning of his   title  : a man who is guided by his intellect—not a zombie guided by feelings, instincts, urges, wishes, whims or revelations. Ending the rule of Attila and the Witch Doctor, he will discard the basic premise that made them possible: the soul-body dichotomy. He will discard its irrational conflicts and contradictions, such as: mind versus heart, thought versus action, reality versus desire, the practical versus the moral. He will be an integrated man, that is: a thinker who is a man of action. He will know that ideas divorced from consequent action are fraudulent, and that action divorced from ideas is suicidal. He will know that the conceptual level of   psycho-epistemology  —the volitional level of reason and thought—is the   basic necessity   of man’s survival and his greatest   moral virtue  . He will know that men need philosophy for the purpose of living on earth.

          The New Intellectual will be a reunion of the twins who should never have been separated: the intellectual and the businessman. He can come from among the best—that is: the most rational—men who may still exist in both camps. In place of an involuntary Witch Doctor and a reluctant Attila, the reunion will produce two new types: the   practical thinker   and the   philosophical businessman  .

          The best among the present intellectuals should consider the tremendous power which they are holding, but have never fully exercised or understood. If any man among them feels that he is the helpless, ineffectual step-son of a “materialistic” culture that grants him neither wealth nor recognition, let him remember the meaning of his title: his power is his intellect, not his feelings, emotions, or intuitions. It is not the businessmen who have robbed him of efficacy, but those of his colleagues who have degraded his profession to the level of soothsayers, tea-leaf readers, and jungle oracles. Let him break with the neo-mystics; let him realize that ideas are not an escape from reality, not a hobby for “disinterested” neurotics in ivory towers, but the most   crucial   and   practical   power in human existence. Then let him become an intellectual leader who assumes full responsibility for the practical consequences of his theories.”

         Sacrilegious is the holistic make up of the pretender who claims to teach. The wanderers who smoke the view; hazed up themselves; benighted, accredited worms of impotency.

Friday, May 1, 2020

Devotional: MAKE CHARACTER YOUR LOUDEST STATEMENT

Poem of the Day: Verses said to be written on the Union by Jonathan Swift

Entries:

         Today 1707, the axe of union between England and Scotland were passed, forming modern Great Britain.

         The fine line that delineates what is important from what is not, the markridge, the bird on the ridge outback.

         Avoid the menacing rhetoric half-sentence plague at cognition halting. It is the desire of they the impudent that lurk in the cold dark to fatigue your . . . Ariadne’s thread.

         Death the one true god, the imperial leader of the brethren.  The force that through the green fuse drives the flower… is my destroyer . DYLAN THOMAS.

         The beauty in aesthetics . . . like this album I’m currently listening to,  Art Angels  by  Grimes  -  World Princess part II  . . . another reason for this input is to protest the not so recent suggestions from the collective hive mind who’s chosen to  reveal  a daunting diminutive explanation: the reason why my dad’s house isn’t painted; a failure as unimpressive, I can’t remember. The subtle unapologetic reason seated on philosophical reason, debauching any subjective contingency I’m slating is a lack of a spiritual umbrella. I quote from Why Beauty Matters by Roger Scruton “ … why beauty matters. It is not just a subjective thing but a universal need of human beings. If we ignore this we find ourselves in a spiritual desert. ” A reflection from my days of ingesting weed, I remember the epiphany from thought stirring, the revelation of abstainment. I had a moment of aha,  now I get it, I shouldn’t stay here . The lack of colour leads to a depravity; a pernicious chronological transition leading to this. I can remember mom saying when she had me for dad, he had no sofa - you know what I mean - and when we moved into ours, we had no tv, mom got the one we used for years, the big inch one he got, barely was used, maybe it broke down, can’t remember. Anyway you get why it was a gradual apprehension, at least in relation to my aging and cognizance of it, the depravity existed in different forms, from the first bungalow with a living room with no curtains to the new house walls he concluded needed no colours.

         Nietzsche knew our capacity to think wasn’t some free floating soul but was embedded in our physiology, constrained by our emotion, shaped by our motivation.

Thursday, May 7, 2020

Devotional: HOW TO HAVE A GOOD DAY

Poem of the Day: The Pobble Who Has No Toes by Edward Lear

Entries:

         Today, it is a neurotic day outside, but in here, it’s fine. I will be musing on what it was like with the silence, the fellowship of self, the devotion to the wonder.

Night Visions:

         I dreamt of Stephanie this morning; it is a crazy one. We must have all started from the trap house, as we were on the lane heading away from there. I don’t ever visit that part of town for anything other than buying crack. There seemed to be a multitude behind us, a crowd of strangers, but it wasn’t overly contradicting; this crowd. If I had fans, they’d be in there. We had made it quite far from the trap house. On a motorcycle, three minutes, maybe. And now, we were close to the roundabout. We weren’t on the wrong side of the road, there is a ditch to the left, and by the right, is the other lane leading back to the trap house. Nothing was out of place, but slowly, the ground clambered, as if, it too had developed legs of its own. Strangely we all continued as if defying gravity. It was so cool, as I could see the big ditch, with those weird eyes that see the whole dream as a whole. I just went on like the others, I felt like Superman, as if aware and knowing of something more.

         Dreams are like stories from a bunch of random cut out stencils. Next, we were under a flyover. No flyover actually exist there, instead a roundabout, then I was in an art studio, and in a laboratory; the final destination. There, I felt out of place, and woke up later. Good convalesce if you ask me?

Tuesday, May 12, 2020

Devotional: KINDNESS IS ALWAYS THE RIGHT RESPONSE

Poem of the Day: On a Lane in Spring by John Clare

Entries:

         First, I must say, this is the first time I’m having a serendipity of this nature. But It’s safe to say, in the final analysis of things, there is a beautiful seam woven, drawn through all things; not as a delineator but as a hitch. I’m not one to root for the concepts of synchronicity as an objective way of analysing perceptual inference—for mental health reasons. But an allusion to its nature can be a fond conclusion for the uninitiated—the untrained mind. The psychoanalytic methodology of dream interpretation is sacrosanct in understanding events, or more broadly: the articulated sphere of being. I skimmed a book in the arts, and to that, it suggested dreams mean nothing; madness you will find there. In point, the event of this morning—my inability to restrain myself—leading to a little outburst, a result of my emotional frustration at the constant discord reactions; a misjudgement of the constant frivolities, including chores. My opinionated ideas on the importance of a family’s need for an ideal that supports a conduct that reflects success is paramount. It’s important the individual doesn’t lose sense of his identity. A dream says a lot and I had one—a reminder, to never walk naked.

Sunday, May 17, 2020

Devotional: THE STOIC IS A WORK IN PROGRESS

Poem of the Day: A Handsome Young Fellow Called Frears by Michael Palin

Entries:

Dang, listening to Jessica Andrea, I’m melting. Rousing emotions of the first album’s stream. I wish I had all that back, but hey I still get something right? Hate the attempts at cognitive narrowing, an attempt at leaving me a fodder, and constant harassment. My only inference being the not needed biological dad in my life to feel safe, sheltered or any of all that.

         Weed was pernicious, I had to stop.

         I learned the  Lo-Shu  and created one for myself. It follows a simple rule, all rows, columns, and diagonals add up to 15, the centre numbers must be odd numbers—the yang of the  Lo-Shu —the four corners must be even numbers—the yin of the  Lo-Shu .

         I learned the technique of solving the unknown values of a rectangle, using the square method - knowledge of area squares and rectangles - really interesting. Yeah, I was cracking for a while, tinkering with formulae,  figuring it out . To think of how desolate the militants of cognitive deterrence acted, switching the scales between the blacks - the pentatonic - and white - the diatonic, hampering in intention, alluding to the parity of my own task consequence. I will remain on this journey, improving cognition, severing all psychotic tendency.

Monday, May 18, 2020

Devotional: HOW YOU DO ANYTHING IS HOW YOU DO EVERYTHING

Poem of the Day: Matilda: Who Told Lies, and was Burned to Death by Hilaire Belloc

Entries:

         Listening to c2.0, putting to words my thoughts on suicide. I’ll be getting some sum to purchase the lethal dose I need for the satire. The hubris of my defiance. I shall not bow to the state in ignorance, peeling off the lump of my hoarded pain, letting it all in a glow. I get to listen to the new album of the 1975. it’ll be a memorable late moment. Well it’s sad, I won’t get to listen to Charli XCX albums, sigh! but hey, so many delights in the world right? I’ll miss them all. I think if I’ll be dying, I should keep all my journals and make them unavailable, create a random password and get that shit locked somewhere . . . won’t say.

         Okay, I will be having a thought swivel, I guess I’ve got the key. Thanks Charli XCX, your albums are legit the SHIT! Oh fvck, Kim Petras is on this OH FVCK the CRiticS! I like.

         Of all that I’ve read so far in the introductory chapter - the beginning - of the book “a brief history of mathematical thought” this has me rapt:  mathematical truths are of a piece with the only world we can know, even if they are further abstracted from experience than most of the truths we are interested in… physical reality is not the same as our conception of it. From our perceptual inference there can be no infinitely precise truth, conversely there can be unambiguous deductions.

         A beautiful quote from the same book, it induces a deep sense of identity, an affirmation of the intrinsic nature of the symmetrical mirror of nature and consciousness in a way that still, delineates  ‘In arithmetic we are not concerned with objects which we come to know as something alien from without through the medium of the senses, but with objects given directly to our reason and, as its nearest kin, utterly transparent to it.’ — Gottlob Frege, 1848–1925

Night Visions:

         I had a night vision of my dad trying to dispose the palm of the coconut tree, but instead of having it tossed over the gate, as is his custom, in front of the house, he topples it over the fence, into the next compound. While trying to do this with its stalk, its rear end, just left in view, still in the compound, it hits him in the head and he falls lifeless on the ground - unconscious - strange right? Well I ran up to him, shouting out almost, I felt less emotion, well, as a viewer.

         I think I may just be at a crossroad, seeing the outcome of trying to hurt someone else, when it isn’t necessary. Moving forward, regardless of whatever is thrown at me, I will remain in my secret place; unperturbed, not going down the same lane of the disturber.

Wednesday, May 20, 2020

Devotional: QUALITY OVER QUANTITY

Poem of the Day: The Mouse’s Tale by Lewis Carroll

Entries:

         A look into the meta-cognition of my behavioural tendencies up to the point of quitting my job as led me on the voyage of seeking out intellectuals from the present, past in a bid to understand the proclivities of my unmeditated expressions, an allusion to the almost insufferable commitment to a life that eludes the being of experience. A look into the psycho-epistemological surges. As arbitrary as the need for understanding, is the memorability of these tendencies. An excerpt from the book The Romanticism Manifesto gives weight:  It has been said and written by many commentators that the atmosphere of the Western world before World War I is incommunicable to those who have not lived in that period. I used to wonder how men could say it, know it, yet give it up—until I observed more closely the men of my own and the preceding generations. They had given it up and, along with it, they had given up everything that makes life worth living: conviction, purpose, values, future. They were drained, embittered hulks whimpering occasionally about the hopelessness of life. Whatever spiritual treason they had committed, they could not accept the cultural sewer of the present, they could not forget that they had once seen a higher, nobler possibility. Unable or unwilling to grasp what had destroyed it, they kept cursing the world, or kept calling men to return to meaningless dogmas, such as religion and tradition, or kept silent. Unable to stifle their vision or to fight for it, they took the “easy” way out: they renounced valuing. To fight, in this context, means: to think.  I chose to fight, to think.

N.B Only I can understand this.

Thursday, May 21, 2020

Devotional: WHAT KIND OF BOXER ARE YOU

Poem of the Day: Friends by Polly Clark

Entries:

         Halo, I didn’t get to read the psycho-epistemological discourse on art yesterday, there was no electricity, I will today though.

         I learned today the cause of trends, it’s philosophy . . . from the Romantic Manifesto of art by Ayn Rand.

         An excerpt from a reading of the Romantic Manifesto by Ayn Rand:  The course of mankind’s   progress   is not a straight, automatic line, but a tortuous struggle, with long detours or relapses into the stagnant night of the irrational. Mankind moves forward by the grace of those   human bridges   who are able to   grasp and transmit  , across years or centuries, the achievements men had reached—and to carry them further.  A representation of what I hope my life represents, leaving my job to understand my roots, better building on my persona, understanding what ticks, and curbing ticks that deter motion in progress.

         I think it’s safe to say; draw the consensus, that the phenomenon discussed earlier in this journal is finally understood, the constant insurgency and disturbance well known, is a direct result of the detour of the human into a subterranean sensory level of awareness, a state that is sub-perceptual—the decline into the sub-animal, the acculturation to the barbaric.

         A fact to keep with me as I progress, is the fact that art, like literature is not a social endeavour, a reminder to revoke the impose in surfeit of the  darkseid .

         The constant suggestions and tries at “elucidating”   or analysing art—music, movies, etc. — is a contrived attempt at impeding the growth of the individual, the insularly altruistic nature of the avatar by agents with sub-animal agendas. This voids the individual of the much needed expression of the mind through art. A crime of the spirit.

Friday, May 22, 2020

Devotional: TODAY IS THE DAY

Poem of the Day: Today Is Very Boring by Jack Prelutsky

Entries:

         Building on from my last input yesterday, I draw the apparency of its connotation to the fabric of everyday living, it’s said, Lana Del Rey I think:  Life imitates art , or  Art imitates life —not sure which—this suffice to say the need to treat life like art, staying away from their concoctions, not remaining amenable to their indifference, striving for re-establishment of order even on a maladaptive level.

         Started the reading of the manifesto of art: The psycho-epistemology of art.

An important definition for future reference.

Psycho-epistemology is the study of man’s cognitive processes from the aspect of the interaction between the conscious mind and the automatic functions of the subconscious.

         Reading the fore-mentioned book, relives me of the memory of a neighbour I’d ride with in the morning to my place of intern. We discussed on a certain day, and she dropped it on me: the inability to control people. I guess she meant: to understand. For understanding comes before the former. Here is the quote.  Human character—with all of its innumerable potentialities, virtues, vices, inconsistencies, contradictions—is so complex that man is his own most bewildering enigma. It is very difficult to isolate and integrate human traits even into purely cognitive abstractions and to bear them all in mind when seeking to understand the men one meets.

         It’s 9:36 P.M and I just finished the topic: The Psycho Epistemology of Art. Great.

Saturday, May 23, 2020

Devotional: SHOW ME HOW TO LIVE

Poem of the Day: A Tragic Story by William Makepeace Thackeray

Entries:

         Drawing from knowledge of Silvano Arieti, I’d like to stately state that the ongoing input is as much a narration of a coincidental incident as it is a pathological way of seeing things—an insight not susceptible to consensual validation.

         Today is my birthday and it’s been a gradual tide leading to the strange, unique ways I’ve come to infer the past couple of days resources—my daily readings—being inclinedly surreal, as much as it’s been beautiful. Yesterday concludes the age of the alphabet, now am on a: define your . . . as personal knowledge increases. My only addition to this is the last timeline from the last phase—the poem audio file—it ends 04:19:33. The digits 419 represent the part of the state law of Nigeria that holds citizens to bear on the laws on fraud. Remembering—not recording in the journal—the epithet from the concluded topic on the psycho-epistemology of art, it ends on the note of  the sense of life , citing primitive forms of philosophy like religion, its many myths, and allegories on man’s existence, like the myth of a supernatural recorder from whom nothing can be hidden, who lists all of a man’s deeds. It affirms the principle of staying grounded—not out of kilter—to one’s moral. Back in Dubai my moral volition hit crossroads, almost closing in on a debacle. I think the 33 stands for a transcendence. I can say now I stand in a better place. The merciless recorder is the integrating mechanism of a man’s subconscious; the record, his sense of life.

         Been coming across a lot of Kafkaesque books, the first I’m aware of is  The Room , I plan on reading  The bridegroom was a dog  by Yoko Tawada.

         With the ever growing disparity between I and most of my peers, it’s quite in parse to say I developed a precociousness for reading and bewilderment.

         Careful, lest you get stuck amongst the thorns of gnawing tendrils of self-imposing persons with identity-ramming as their precursor to relation.

Monday, May 25, 2020

Devotional: WHERE TO FIND JOY

Poem of the Day: from The Ballad of Reading Gaol by Oscar Wilde

Entries:

         This being the second time quoting this sentence from the manifesto, drawing from a new percept — the letters in bold .  Religion being a primitive form, and attempt, at normative abstraction, with a tinge of a foreshadowing; a subtle hum, a call to peer into, at something more.

          SINCE religion is a primitive form of philosophy—an attempt to offer a comprehensive view of reality—many of its myths are distorted,   dramatized allegories   based on some element of truth, some actual,   if profoundly elusive  , aspect of man’s existence.

         The astonishing discovery at the realization of the fact that a cone has a pointed top and circular base, not a circular top hollowed tapering off to its base at a point.

         Morals have nothing to do with sociality.

         Art is a selective re-creation of reality according to an artist’s metaphysical value-judgments.

         An example of a perfect integration and projection of a normative abstraction is Jesus from the bible. An allusion to a statement from the psycho-epistemology of art is the failure of the law of Moses.  An exhaustive philosophical treatise defining moral values, with   a long list of virtues   to be practiced, will not do it; it will not convey what an ideal man would be like and how he would act: no mind can deal with so immense a sum of abstractions. When I say “deal with” I mean retranslate all the abstractions into the perceptual concretes for which they stand—i.e., reconnect them to reality—and hold it all in the focus of one’s conscious awareness. There is no way to integrate such a sum without projecting an actual human figure—an integrated concretization that illuminates the theory and makes it intelligible.  Another quote:  Moral principles remain in their minds as floating abstractions, offering them a goal they cannot grasp and demanding that they reshape their souls in its image, thus leaving them with a burden of undefinable moral guilt. Art is the indispensable medium for the communication of a moral ideal.  Jesus is a beautiful attempt at well-crafted art. A model for Christians.  Without the assistance of art, ethics remains in the position of theoretical engineering: art is the model-builder.

Tuesday, May 26, 2020

Entries:

         It should be no cue, as my instinctive decision to severe ties with old mates is a no brainer. My choice to spend time with a friend on his birthday led him, and not just his league of pals, but also a girl I’d held dear for a while, to sift through my actions for reckless volitions. An attack on what is most dear—my identity. The repudiation of a need for consciousness in wakefulness; the allure of blackout through an impersonation of my recent character, reiterated to me in conscious awakening. A foolproof frame-up to suggest of excesses ungrounded. Here goes another set of quotes from the Romantic Manifesto on Art:  One of the distinguishing characteristics of a work of art (including literature) is that it serves no practical, material end, but is an end in itself; it serves no purpose other than contemplation—and the pleasure of that contemplation is so intense, so deeply personal that a man experiences it as a self-sufficient, self-justifying primary and, often, resists or resents any suggestion to analyse it: the suggestion, to him, has the quality of an attack on his identity, on his deepest, essential self.

          No human emotion can be causeless, nor can so intense an emotion be causeless, irreducible, and unrelated to the source of emotions (and of values): to the needs of a living entity’s survival. Art does have a purpose and does serve a human need; only it is not a material need, but a need of man’s consciousness. Art is inextricably tied to man’s survival—not to his physical survival, but to that on which his physical survival depends: to the preservation and survival of his consciousness.

         Note all these in light of my art. The attack on the validity of my artistic expression—denial of the efficacy of my consciousness; the negation of my fundamental understanding of reality—as a prelude to that which is essential—my consciousness. The defaming statement:  you said, consciousness isn’t important  is a direct inciting, a proposing of minimal intelligence—this being a form of the sub-animal, the instinctive, a semi-conscious wielding of a half-arsed brain wasted away, failed on abstinence; repetitive drug use—being smug okay in guiding and volitive excogitation.

         I should remember the need; and utmost—to know of the things important, the things that matter most—is non-social. To remain conscious of this is important, as the inherent mode of intelligence in itself is insular, constantly regressing and gaining obsoleteness in ever growing complexity. The constant abstraction and assimilation of newly understood concepts is to redefine perceptual inference, the intuitive, and is to reprogram the subconscious. Intelligence in humans without conscious wielding is instinctive—impulse driven, a process, a form of distortion—and not learning, not progressive, it’s to return to the primitive, to leave evolution to the natural selection—a task of billion years. It doesn’t improvise.

         Altruism the cancer of the 21st century, the cancerous outgrowth in communities; the birth child of culture.  One of the grimmest monuments to altruism is man’s culturally induced selflessness: his willingness to live with himself as with the unknown, to ignore, evade, repress the personal (the non-social) needs of his soul, to know least about the things that matter most, and thus to consign his deepest values to the impotent underground of subjectivity and his life to the dreary wasteland of chronic guilt.  One of the lethal contamination of the arts is the gradual pernicious encroachment; the spread of false ideals: culturally induced selflessness, the enjoyment of intelligible aesthetics, the failure to fight; to think. If art is the model-builder, what models are being churned out by modern culture? If this is true:  The basic purpose of art is not to teach, but to show—to hold up to man a concretized image of his nature and his place in the universe.  What image is being represented.

         How about a game of speak and kill, a peek a boo, Sermo Liber Vita Ipsa.

Monday, October 26, 2020

Devotional: THREE PARTS, ONE AIM

Poem of the Day: Love After Love by Derek Walcott

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Wonder

Today's Musical: SONATA IN A MAJOR, KK 208 BY DOMENICO SCARLATTI (1685–1757)

Entries:

         Today is a great day, I was so mad at Jess yesterday, I sent her a mail filled with my upset rants. Earlier, I had sent her a mail talking about discerning meaning of words, it turns out today’s devotional speaks about that. Three parts of philosophy it says we have, the moral, the natural, and the  rational , what I’m interested in here is the rational that says words should be discerned properly. I guess it remains tethered. I discover the day’s poet as also being an interest as I proceeded. I will post quotes of him found.

 Break a vase, and the love that reassembles the fragments is stronger than that love which took its symmetry for granted when it was whole.

 The English language is nobody's special property. It is the property of the imagination: it is the property of the language itself.

 Visual surprise is natural in the Caribbean; it comes with the landscape, and faced with its beauty, the sigh of History dissolves.

The last quote is great, I must say though, Derek Walcott looks familiar, leading me to search for his doppelganger.

Saturday, October 31, 2020

Devotional: YOU WERE BORN GOOD

Poem of the Day: from Hallowe’en by John Kendrick Bangs

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

For Us, Who Dare Not Dare

Today's Musical: MISSA PAPAE MARCELLI 1. KYRIE BY GIOVANNI PIERLUIGI DA PALESTRINA (1525–1594)

Entries:

         Here is a musing from days back:

          The gibes I have to deal with all day from the prestidigitators, their obsequious lethargic ugly strident cries of malevolent despair, most times camouflaged with a pretence of superiority, in difference; the poisoning of the blood stream. In mask switching; the hail of being similar besides the difference. The dreaming; being the articulation of my thoughts, as they appear, brightest when adorned as they could be with actions. How adorned are your thoughts?

          I meet up with myself in these writings, when questions are asked. My inner dialogue like a lake frozen, still waiting for the thaw season. The thaw season like every season, ephemeral, changing, as thoughts beg to be adorned in different ways. In action, in writing, in contemplation ... The thaw season the allegorical element to be left for contemplation. A cycle I think.

          If all these didn't happen, maybe that pinball ball would have destroyed me, a daemon process insisting to remain online, unsure of its validity, not out of a lack of resource; an incapability to keep running, an unwillingness to be the tributary.

          Like having a point of view and choosing not to have a point of view, my current dialectical opinion being of the opinion that one understanding of a system isn't good enough for understanding all systems. Put simply.

Tuesday, September 22, 2020

Devotional: NO PAIN, NO GAIN

Poem of the Day: An Old Woman of the Roads by Padraic Colum

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

To A Freedom Fighter

Today's Musical: WER DANK OPFERT, DER PREISET MICH – HE WHO GIVES THANKS, PRAISES ME, CANTATA BWV 17 PART 2, NO. 7 CHORALE: ‘WIE SICH EIN VATER ERBARMET’ – ‘AS A FATHER HAS MERCY’ BY JOHANN SEBASTIAN BACH (1685–1750)

Entries:

         It’s a good morning, Jess has me always, on waking up today she has three stories on Instagram, and she cues on brushing before sleeping, only for me to wake up with a slight tooth ache, weird right? She deletes the story shortly though. It’s good to be back journaling.

         My ego has been hurt before, and it made me cry. I've been without love; the longing for, it trickled, but not once have I under prodding or swat in psychological anguish—maybe lasering down to the moment’s hit, it almost welled up, but never with too many hits in succession—coiled away. These thoughts appeared why listening to the Chromatica album, Sine from above; my first listen. Sucks hey, at least you make em cry, it’s worse dear.

Wednesday, September 23, 2020

Devotional: THE MOST SECURE FORTRESS

Poem of the Day: Digging by Edward Thomas

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

Riot: 60's

Today's Musical:

Entries:

         Today is a great day, even though I can’t get the tablet with me to work, not sure why, I’ll be returning it to its owner. I sent series of messages to Jess through mail, and I’m studying the day’s reading of poems, it’s 10:25 A.M.

         Today is the autumn equinox, marking the day of almost equal day and night across almost every area of the earth, the word equinox literally means equal night. Today’s poem discusses the smells traditionally associated with this season. Also the tropical zodiac timeline—Libra begins, ending 23rd of October. I hope to getting to study the zodiac and its signs before the year runs out.

         All day I have to deal with tripe from at least 6 people, it used to be torture but, now it’s effrontery building, and as casual as my meals. Northing perturbing.

         I’m hoping I get better, learn to leave the hurt behind, become better, heal, leave the hell behind me, and cultivate forbearance.

         My neighbours can, kind of hear my thoughts, so they are about impeding the analytical process by sound distractions. My knowledge from examination of its effect is, its lack of influence in the arrival of original thoughts.

Thursday, September 24, 2020

Devotional: IT COULD HAPPEN TO YOU

Poem of the Day: Autumn Fires by Robert Louis Stevenson

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

We Saw Beyond Our Seeming

Today's Musical: LES BARICADES MISTÉRIEUSES BY FRANÇOIS COUPERIN (1668–1733) ARR. THOMAS ADÈS (B. 1971)

Entries:

         Today, like every day of the past few months starts with the unappealing voices of the . . . holding my peace, stroking what’s left of my mental sanity. I heard so many voices listening to a song this morning, it was saddening, but I do it for me, not for anyone. The voices I guess keeps my inner-dialogue, and reminds me there is much to behaviour than self-talk.

Here is the message I sent to Jessica yesterday:

 Can you save my heavy dirty soul from me? how's your day been?

 So here is what happened . . . Last week Tuesday I was away to a neighbouring state, it's called Osun, I was posted there for the NYSC program years back, it starts with a 3 weeks compound camping, after which I'm dispatched to a local district for a year program, but first I was to go home, take care of my needs. On getting back to Lagos before leaving for my house, I receive a phone call from my friend informing me on how he still needs me to come see him, we'd been talking for a while about me coming to spend time around. I arrive at his place; he resides in a hotel—he's from outside the state. I was with him a while, when I inform him on the program I was writing then, it's a publishing platform software, I had zipped a copy of it on my phone, it being the only thing I thought of all through the camping. He was happy and bit surprised to know I had started writing programs—we had been crack-buddies, tinkering with paid software back in uni. He informs me of a colleague who is currently working on a startup—we graduated the previous year—and how he's going in as a tech assistant, he implores me to join the train so I do. I sat in for the interview, and got employed. Few months in, the man—the colleague's uncle—wants me to work on the publishing platform for him. Two years later, I'm working with a startup I co-founded, and the NYSC program is totally out of view, it being the single program I need to get employed in the country. It was a total blow off. On quitting my startup due to the insidious effect of daily weed smoking and a new growing two, three months habit of crack, I decided to quit, on seeing my inability to stay away. Better to cut my money supply I thought. I had stayed clean for months, but working on a mixtape and having friends who smoked, popped pills, I never was a popper, it was difficult, and hey there had been some cool songs on staying sober, like Dance to this by Troye Sivan. lol.

 On coming home, I had some new gigs, but I lost them all because my dad promised I was going for a Master’s program in Dubai, I couldn't 'cause I guess he tricked me, I don't trust him. I'm back, was supposed to leave for USA then the pandemic hits, what a crease. Here is the reason why I left for Osun to ascertain the state of the NYSC program.

 In my freestyle I said something about being locked up with still no serving, I had no idea I said that at the time, my thoughts betray me always, sad.

 The dudes in the state; the officers in charge of the re-mobilization program, had me pay back the allowances I got paid, two months before I absconded, why you may say? Because it was much of a strife for my comfortable lifestyle *coughs*. I just couldn't take the ride down, it was hours, but that wasn't it. I had been betrayed by my work colleagues on my last travel, my software had been pitched in the weekly weekend meetings. In perspective, it was what I interviewed with, I showed the "colleague's" uncle. It just wasn't fair to be treated that way. Meeting him, confronting him stating clearly that it was intellectual theft to have the company build a software I had started, being younger then and, naive I couldn't get into a proper deal with him, I settled for you'll be fine, and there was a great recording studio, a medium state of the art sorta, and I lived on premises, so I got opportunities to practice, though I never got to, I was way too busy writing the program.

 Well, these folks are weird you know, he has me leave with the original copy of the issued receipt and, honestly I just knew something was off, his motions betrayed him, but hey why read meanings to things right? On getting back home I get into a I'm not down for this conversation with my dad and mail the PR section of the program, asking to be informed on what I was to do with the receipts, I had been told by the accountant to expect a call and a text message, this being the traditional way of announcements. It was some weird correspondence being I'd take on a more stilted approach with my word use. Nothing serious just a call of attention to the CC marker.

 He sends me a message on Monday saying I was saying nonsense; sending messages to offices I had no business. All I did was follow instructions, on sending a request for publicly needed information, I was told to follow a link to complete my registration, I got a notification response stating my ineligibility to use the application and to report it to the state office, which I did.

 The awful thing is, now I have to travel again, to submit the papers. Whose fault is that? Maybe mine for not being all knowing.

 That's pretty much it.

Saturday, September 26, 2020

Devotional: WHAT TIME OFF IS FOR

Poem of the Day: Wild Geese by Mary Oliver

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

No No No No

Today's Musical: DU BIST DIE RUH – YOU ARE PEACE, D. 776 BY FRANZ SCHUBERT (1797–1828)

Entries:

         It’s 11:24 P.M and I have a reason to believe things are going the way they should, I sent mails earlier this morning to Jessica, I’ll add a text of it below. Well, explaining what has transpired today, today’s poem is a beautiful representation of how the year has been.

         I'm having cold coffee this morning Jess, I owe a lot to you . . . yeah . . . my sobriety . . . the video with the water bottle, that was it for me . . . I had been cutting out. "I'm done with your OC." I spoke with my dad, I apologized. I'm actually an arse. I guess the hearing voices thing has claimed a shad off my broken character. He was off with the talk of me being really sorry when in full awareness of his proclivities and reasons. It's fine now. I miss you. Will you never send me the video? Armstrong what a wonderful world . . . I've been a penfriend for a while now, I'm actually a lot. lol. You should text me . . . I saw a cut on your hands in a picture, it's been months, the one of you in the scrub’s end of a car, lol. Please remain you. I love you.

Saturday, September 30, 2020

Devotional: YOU CAN’T TOUCH ME

Poem of the Day: Thirty Days Hath September by Anon.

Collected Poems of Maya Angelou:

The Calling of Names

Today's Musical: ‘AU FOND DU TEMPLE SAINT’ – ‘AT THE BACK OF THE HOLY TEMPLE’ FROM THE PEARL FISHERS BY GEORGES BIZET (1838–1875)

Entries:

         Today is a cool day, cool coffee cups, two now, I sent mails to Jess, I’ll include them below:

Sep 29, 2020, 10:23 PM

         Let me introduce myself, my name is Theo. I don't know if you know me, but it's been sockets of stowed hardy balls prying the internet, till I found you. Yes, am I a logic fan? I was, still am, how did that

happen? well, back in university, my friends hit me with all the good stuff and one summer, I was home and really got laid back, I mean talk of laid back, and it happened for me . . .

Today 12:47 PM

         Ooookay . . . the prying part isn't all together true, more like surfing. Forgive my ill pedantry, but my foraging has been a sort of prying ever since . . . um . . . I heard my name in the positivity clip . . . I'd like to write you finishing the previous mail, but Jess I really need to know what it was about the name theonightswan on Instagram and EveValence on Twitter that caught your attention, if it is . . . I guess I didn't . . . I have no idea lol. Jess, I'm not happy. Though nothing could be more excitingly sputtering right now than this little "out of my reality grip" thing you've got going. Remember when I said "How can lies be cues if truth is but an impression, what am I missing?" Yesterday I was by myself. Not really, I never am, it's a bypass usually to articulate my thoughts as close as my frayed, exhausted brain would let me. But yesterday I got to it—I still get to do things lol—and it precipitated up, through all those strands of drenched neurons soaked up in Jess' mirth, and I got it, Now I can't remember, you know why? I figured you understand. The crux of this message is to ascertain, yes you see my messages, oooh he's still on that . . . well what else? No funeral at this ending. Only a rebirth my love . . . you've killed me:)